<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Welcome! on DinAmicI</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Welcome! on DinAmicI</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 16:17:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dai-dinamici.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PhD position in Ergodic Theory at Utrecht University</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/05/phd-position-in-ergodic-theory-at-utrecht-university/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 15:59:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/05/phd-position-in-ergodic-theory-at-utrecht-university/</guid><description>PhD position available in Ergodic Theory at Utrecht University with title Merging Critical Orbits. The position is sponsored by a grant from the Dutch National Science Foundation.
General Description of the intended research:
Matching is a mysterious phenomenon which has recently been observed for several parameterized families of interval maps in the deterministic and random settings. It is the property that for each critical point the (random) orbits of the left and right limit merge after some finite number of steps, and that the (expected value of the) derivatives of both orbits are also equal at that time; this assures the stability of this phenomenon under small perturbations of the parameter.</description></item><item><title>Online Ph.D. course by Albert Fathi, June 2021</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/05/on-line-ph-d-course-by-albert-fathi-june-2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 10:11:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/05/on-line-ph-d-course-by-albert-fathi-june-2021/</guid><description>This online course is part of the Ph.D. program in Mathematics at University of Rome Tor Vergata.
Title: &amp;ldquo;Viscosity solutions of the Hamilton-Jacobi equations on non-compact manifolds&amp;rdquo;
Lecturer: Albert Fathi (Georgia Institute of Technology, USA)
Schedule:
Lecture 1: Tuesday June 1, 11-13 (UTC+2) Lecture 2: Friday June 4, 11-13 (UTC+2) Lecture 3: Tuesday June 15, 11-13 (UTC+2) Lecture 4: Thursday June 17, 11-13 (UTC+2) Lecture 5: Tuesday June 22, 11-13 (UTC+2) Lectures will be streamed by the platform Microsoft Teams.</description></item><item><title>Umberto Zannier (Scuola Normale Superiore, Italy)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/umberto-zannier-scuola-normale-superiore-italy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 08:40:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/umberto-zannier-scuola-normale-superiore-italy/</guid><description>Speaker: Umberto Zannier (Scuola Normale Superiore, Italy)
Title: Torsion values of sections, elliptical billiards and diophantine problems in dynamics
Abstract: After a very brief review of basics on elliptic curves and their families, we shall consider &amp;ldquo;sections&amp;rdquo; of such families, and especially their &amp;ldquo;torsion values&amp;rdquo;. For instance, what can be said of the complex numbers b for which [latex](2, \sqrt{2(2-b)})[/latex] is torsion on the Legendre curve [latex]y^2=x(x-1)(x-b)[/latex]? In particular, we shall recall results of &amp;ldquo;Manin-Mumford type&amp;rdquo; and focus to illustrate some applications to elliptical billiards.</description></item><item><title>PhD Program in Mathematics at Università di Bologna</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/04/phd-program-in-mathematics-at-universita-di-bologna/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 15:06:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/04/phd-program-in-mathematics-at-universita-di-bologna/</guid><description>The call for application for the Ph.D. Program in Mathematics (37th cycle - A.Y. 2021/2022) at Università di Bologna is now open. 7 fellowships are available.
Info about the Ph.D. Program in Mathematics: https://www.unibo.it/en/teaching/phd/2021-2022/mathematics
How to apply (general page): https://www.unibo.it/en/teaching/phd/information-enrolling-phd-programme/how-to-apply-phd-programme
Deadline: May 21, 2021 at 12:00 PM</description></item><item><title>Selim Ghazouani (Université d’Orsay, France)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/selim-ghazouani-universite-dorsay-france/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 21:04:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/selim-ghazouani-universite-dorsay-france/</guid><description>Speaker: **Selim Ghazouani ** (Université d’Orsay, France)
Title: Piecewise affine homeomorphisms of the circle and dilation surfaces
*Abstract: *In this talk I will consider the following question: if one picks a piecewise affine map of the circle &amp;ldquo;at random”, what dynamical behaviour are we likely to observe? The case of standard circle diffeomorphisms has been studied by Herman in the 80s; in this emblematic case the problem can be reduced to theorems close to KAM theory.</description></item><item><title>PhD position at the University of Exeter</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/04/phd-position-at-the-university-of-exeter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 08:52:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/04/phd-position-at-the-university-of-exeter/</guid><description>A new PhD position call has been advertised as part of Prof. Mark Hollands&amp;rsquo;s Marie Sklodowska Curie ITN: Early Stage Researcher grant CriticalEarth: Multiscale Critical Transitions in the Earth System at the University of Exeter (UK).
See https://jobs.exeter.ac.uk/hrpr_webrecruitment/wrd/run/ETREC107GF.open?VACANCY_ID=856279Vhur&amp;amp;WVID=3817591jNg&amp;amp;LANG=USA for the application and for more information.
Deadline: May 5, 2021</description></item><item><title>Tanja Schindler (Scuola Normale Superiore, Italy)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/tanja-schindler-scuola-normale-superiore-italy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 22:04:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/tanja-schindler-scuola-normale-superiore-italy/</guid><description>Speaker: Tanja Schindler (Scuola Normale Superiore, Italy)
Title: Almost sure asymptotic behaviour of Birkhoff sums for infinite measure-preserving dynamical systems
Abstract: We are interested in the limit behaviour of Birkhoff sums over an infinite sigma-finite measure space. If the observable is integrable then &amp;ndash; by a classical theorem by Aaronson &amp;ndash; there exists no sequence of real numbers such that the Birkhoff sum normed by this sequence converges almost surely to 1.</description></item><item><title>RTDb in Mathematical Physics (University of Milano - Bicocca)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/04/rtdb-in-mathematical-physics-university-of-milano-bicocca/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 13:31:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/04/rtdb-in-mathematical-physics-university-of-milano-bicocca/</guid><description>A tenure-track assistant professorship (“RTDb” according to the Italian legislation) has been announced at the Department of Mathematics and Applications, University of Milano - Bicocca.
The research activity will focus on topics in Mathematical Physics. We seek applications from outstanding candidates that can strengthen and expand the group’s domains of expertise, such as candidates with expertise in dynamical systems and their applications, integrable systems and their applications, fluid dynamics, statistical models, quantum mechanics and related mathematical methods.</description></item><item><title>Eva Miranda (Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya) and Daniel Peralta-Salas (Instituto de Ciencias Matemáticas, Spain)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/eva-miranda-universitat-politecnica-de-catalunya-and-daniel-peralta-salas-instituto-de-ciencias-matematicas-spain/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 09:39:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/eva-miranda-universitat-politecnica-de-catalunya-and-daniel-peralta-salas-instituto-de-ciencias-matematicas-spain/</guid><description>Speakers: Eva Miranda (Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya), Daniel Peralta-Salas (Instituto de Ciencias Matemáticas, Spain)
Title: Looking at Euler flows through a contact mirror: Universality and Turing completeness
Abstract: The dynamics of an inviscid and incompressible fluid flow on a Riemannian manifold is governed by the Euler equations. Recently, Tao launched a programme to address the global existence problem for the Euler and Navier Stokes equations based on the concept of universality.</description></item><item><title>Belgrade Summer School on Dynamics, July 17-22, 2021</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/03/belgrade-summer-school-on-dynamics-july-17-22-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 10:44:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/03/belgrade-summer-school-on-dynamics-july-17-22-2021/</guid><description>The Mathematical Institute of the Serbian Academy of Sciences and Arts will host the Belgrade Summer School on Dynamics, July 17-22, 2021, organized by Vladimir Dragović (UTD/MISANU) and Vadim Kaloshin (IST, Austria).
The target audience is undergraduate and graduate students and researchers from Serbia, the region, and around the globe interested in modern dynamics.
The school will be organized online with possible hybrid elements, if the situation with the pandemic permits.</description></item><item><title>Álvaro del Pino Gómez (Utrecht University, The Netherlands)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/alvaro-del-pino-gomez/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 15:14:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/alvaro-del-pino-gomez/</guid><description>Speaker: Álvaro del Pino Gómez (Utrecht University, The Netherlands)
Title: Billiards in subriemannian geometry
Abstract: When one considers manifolds with boundary, billiard dynamics are the natural analogue of standard geodesic dynamics. Namely, instead of having geodesics escape at the boundary, we force them back into the manifold using the reflection law. In other dynamical settings, similar constructions are possible: In 2006, B. Khesin and S. Tabachnikov initiated the study of billiards in the semiriemannian setting, studying the integrability of various tables.</description></item><item><title>RTDb in Probability and Mathematical Statistics (University of Rome Tor Vergata)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/03/rtdb-in-probability-and-mathematical-statistics-university-of-rome-tor-vergata/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 13:27:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/03/rtdb-in-probability-and-mathematical-statistics-university-of-rome-tor-vergata/</guid><description>A tenure-track position (Ricercatore Tempo Determinato di tipo b - RTDb) has been announced at the Department of Mathematics, University of Rome Tor Vergata.
The research activity will focus on topics in the Probability and Mathematical Statistics sector, with particular reference to issues related to Machine Learning, Big Data analysis and Artificial Intelligence.
Announcement and template of application form (in Italian): http://web.uniroma2.it/module/name/Content/newlang/italiano/action/showpage/navpath/CON/content_id/91941/section_id/6206
Deadline: 1 April 2021</description></item><item><title>Applications to the school "Modern Aspects of Dynamical Sytems"</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/03/applications-to-the-school-modern-aspects-of-dynamical-sytems/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 09:41:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/03/applications-to-the-school-modern-aspects-of-dynamical-sytems/</guid><description>This is to announce that applications to the Fondazione CIME school “Modern Aspects of Dynamical Systems”, first announced here and rescheduled to 2-6 August 2021, are now open until May 31, 2021.
Please be aware that, based on the epidemic situation, it is yet to be confirmed that the school will take place and in which form.
For all information on the courses of the school, news about the schedule, and how to apply, visit the website http://web.</description></item><item><title>Postdoc positions at GSSI (L'Aquila)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/02/2-post-doc-positions-in-mathematics-at-gssi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 08:17:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/02/2-post-doc-positions-in-mathematics-at-gssi/</guid><description>GSSI (L&amp;rsquo;Aquila, Italy) announces two postdoc positions for one or more of the following profiles: Numerical methods for Partial differential equations and Dynamical systems, Numerical linear algebra, Mathematical models in Fluid dynamics and Biology, Partial Differential Equations in Mathematical Physics, Models of collective behavior, dynamics on networks. Stochastic differential equations, stochastic methods in statistical mechanics, hydrodynamic limits. Computational methods in seismology with experience in HPC. Mathematical methods for quantum computing, mathematics in quantum cryptography.</description></item><item><title>Alessandro Della Corte (Università di Camerino, Italy)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/alessandro-della-corte-universita-di-camerino-italy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 16:22:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/alessandro-della-corte-universita-di-camerino-italy/</guid><description>Speaker: Alessandro Della Corte (Università di Camerino, Italy)
Title: The simplest erasing substitution
*Abstract: *The symbolic action of a substitution on the binary expansion generates naturally an interval map. In case of erasing substitutions, the map is typically Baire-1 and not Darboux. As a model case, we consider what is arguably the simplest erasing substitution, mapping 0s to the empty word and 1s to 0 or 1 depending on the parity.</description></item><item><title>Contributed talks in Dynamical Systems at ICMP 2021, Geneva, August 2021</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/02/contributed-talks-in-dynamical-systems-at-icmp-2021-geneva-august-2021/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 12:24:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/02/contributed-talks-in-dynamical-systems-at-icmp-2021-geneva-august-2021/</guid><description>The organizers of the Dynamical Systems Thematic Session of the International Congress on Mathematical Physics (2-7 August 2021, Geneva) especially invite young researchers to apply for a contributed talk and/or a poster in the session.
Application form: https://www.icmp2021.com/financial-support-2/
Deadline: 8 March 2021</description></item><item><title>Paolo Giulietti (Università di Pisa, Italy)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/paolo-giulietti-universita-di-pisa-italy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 15:15:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/paolo-giulietti-universita-di-pisa-italy/</guid><description>Speaker: Paolo Giulietti (Università di Pisa, Italy)
Title: Infinite mixing for accessible skew products
*Abstract: *I will present some decay of correlations results on skew products which are locally accessible. The results rely on the study of a twisted transfer operator and could be generalized to many other situations. I will also present numerical counterparts to such results.
NOTE: The seminar will be streamed live on our YouTube channel then saved there.</description></item><item><title>Postdocs in Nice</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/02/postdocs-at-university-of-nice/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 17:59:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/02/postdocs-at-university-of-nice/</guid><description>Université Côte d’Azur in Nice (France) advertises several postdoc positions for young researchers, in the framework of the program: ‘‘AIDES INDIVIDUELLES JEUNES CHERCHEURS 2021&amp;quot;
For more information: https://univ-cotedazur.fr/medias/fichier/aap-post-doc-ucajedi-2021_1612864265768-pdf</description></item><item><title>Gary Froyland (University of New South Wales, Australia)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/gary-froyland-university-of-new-south-wales-australia/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 12:12:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/gary-froyland-university-of-new-south-wales-australia/</guid><description>Speaker: Gary Froyland (University of New South Wales, Australia)
Title: The dynamic ocean
Abstract: The circulation of our oceans strongly influences climate, weather and biology. Our ocean currents are dynamic, and fluctuate to varying extents. I will introduce data-driven numerical tools that can tease apart dynamic components of the ocean, with information sourced from ocean drifters, satellite imagery, and ocean models. These components, their lifecycles, and their response to external forcing, help us to build a dynamic picture of our ocean.</description></item><item><title>Misha Bialy (Tel Aviv University, Israel)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/mischa-bialy-tel-aviv-university-israel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 08:29:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/mischa-bialy-tel-aviv-university-israel/</guid><description>Speaker: **Misha Bialy ** (Tel Aviv University, Israel)
Title: Birkhoff-Poritsky conjecture for centrally-symmetric billiards
Abstract: In this talk I shall discuss Birkhoff-Poritsky conjecture for centrally-symmetric C^2-smooth convex planar billiards. We assume that the domain A between the invariant curve of 4-periodic orbits and the boundary of the phase cylinder is foliated by C^0-invariant curves. Under this assumption we prove that the billiard curve is an ellipse. Other versions of Birkhoff-Poritsky conjecture follow from this result.</description></item><item><title>Postdocs in Moscow</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/01/postdocs-in-moscow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 19:41:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/01/postdocs-in-moscow/</guid><description>The Faculty of Mathematics (FM) of the Higher School of Economics (HSE University), Moscow, invites applications for postdoctoral research positions in Mathematics and Mathematical Physics. Appointments are normally made for one year. Postdoctoral fellows have an opportunity to renew their contract (no more than twice).
The position involves:
• joining one of our research groups within the FM in performing high-quality research – every successful candidate will be offered a position in the FM;</description></item><item><title>Michele Gianfelice (Università della Calabria, Italy)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/michele-gianfelice-universita-della-calabria-italy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 13:27:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/michele-gianfelice-universita-della-calabria-italy/</guid><description>Speaker: Michele Gianfelice (Università della Calabria, Italy)
Title: Stochastic stability of classical Lorenz flow under impulsive type forcing
*Abstract: *Inspired by the problem of modeling the so called anthropogenic forcing in climatology, e.g. the effects of the emissions of greenhouse gases in the atmosphere, we introduce a novel type of random perturbation for the classical Lorenz flow and prove its stochastic stability. The perturbation acts on the system in an impulsive way, hence is not of diffusive type.</description></item><item><title>PhD position in Groningen</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/01/phd-position-in-groningen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 14:35:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/01/phd-position-in-groningen/</guid><description>A new PhD position call has been advertised as part of Marcello Seri&amp;rsquo;s grant on spectral aspects of magnetic fields via sub-Riemannian geometry at the University of Groningen (Netherlands).
See https://www.rug.nl/about-ug/work-with-us/job-opportunities/?details=00347-02S00080XP for the application and for more information. The lecture by Marcello Seri at the Dutch Differential Topology &amp;amp; Geometry online seminar can provide additional context to the interested applicants: https://www.few.vu.nl/~trt800/ddtg.html.
Deadline: February 28, intended starting date May 1. (Students who will obtain their Master degree in the summer are welcome to apply.</description></item><item><title>Andrea Venturelli (Université d’Avignon, France)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/andrea-venturelli-universite-davignon-france/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 09:00:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/andrea-venturelli-universite-davignon-france/</guid><description>Speaker: Andrea Venturelli (Université d’Avignon, France)
Title: Hyperbolic motion in the Newtonian N-body problem with arbitrary limit shape
*Abstract: *We prove for the N-body problem the existence of hyperbolic motions for any prescribed limit shape and any given initial configuration of the bodies. The energy level h&amp;gt;0 of the motion can also be chosen arbitrarily. Our approach is based on the construction of a global viscosity solutions for the Hamilton-Jacobi equation H(x,du(x))=h.</description></item><item><title>PhD or postdoc positions in Leiden</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/01/phd-or-postdoc-positions-in-leiden/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 14:31:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2021/01/phd-or-postdoc-positions-in-leiden/</guid><description>The Mathematical Institute of the Faculty of Science, Leiden University, is looking for
15 PhD candidates and postdocs in Mathematics
Project description: The Mathematical Institute of Leiden University invites applicants for a PhD or postdoc position in any of the research areas of the institute, which are Algebra, Geometry and Number Theory; Analysis and Dynamical Systems; Probability Theory; and Statistics. Contacting supervisors within the MI before applying is encouraged. The position comes with some light teaching duties.</description></item><item><title>Postdocs in Rome Sapienza</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/12/postdocs-in-rome-sapienza/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 08:58:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/12/postdocs-in-rome-sapienza/</guid><description>The Department of Mathematics of Sapienza Università di Roma has opened calls for a 1-year postdoctoral position and two 2-year postdoctoral positions, in all areas of Mathematics. The candidates must submit their own research projects.
Deadline: January 20, 2021
Formal announcements and info (in Italian) about the positions and application procedure are found here:
1-year position: https://web.uniroma1.it/trasparenza/dettaglio_bando_albo/168016
2-year positions: https://web.uniroma1.it/trasparenza/dettaglio_bando_albo/168015
An unofficial guide in English through the application procedure for the 2-year positions is available at: https://sites.</description></item><item><title>Symplectic Structures in Geometry, Algebra and Dynamics 2021-24</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/12/symplectic-structures-in-geometry-algebra-and-dynamics-2021-24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 17:54:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/12/symplectic-structures-in-geometry-algebra-and-dynamics-2021-24/</guid><description>The German Research Foundation has granted the funding of a Collaborative Research Centre / Transregio (CRC/TRR 191) on Symplectic Structures in Geometry, Algebra and Dynamics. This CRC is based at the universities of Bochum, Cologne and Heidelberg, and it includes mathematicians from Aachen University.
Within this CRC, 17 individual projects will be funded. The funding comprises: 12 full-time postdoctoral positions (pd) and 24 positions for doctoral students (ds).
Currently we have openings for 4 postdoctoral positions (pd) and 12 positions for doctoral students (ds).</description></item><item><title>How to become a member of the UMI Unit DinAmicI</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/12/how-to-become-a-member-of-the-umi-unit-dinamici/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 17:29:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/12/how-to-become-a-member-of-the-umi-unit-dinamici/</guid><description>As you may remember (see here) DinAmicI is now also a unit of the Italian Mathematical Union (UMI).
If you are a member of UMI, or you are planning to become one, we invite you to officially join our unit by filling in the form that you find at https://umi.dm.unibo.it/gruppi-umi-2/.
For more information please contact Claudio Bonanno at claudio.bonanno@unipi.it</description></item><item><title>Postdoc in Dynamical Systems at Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/12/postdoc-in-dynamical-systems-at-vrije-universiteit-amsterdam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 06:47:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/12/postdoc-in-dynamical-systems-at-vrije-universiteit-amsterdam/</guid><description>The Department of Mathematics of Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam welcomes applications for a three-year Postdoctoral position in Dynamical Systems, including (but not limited to) computational dynamics, data driven dynamics, network dynamics and evolutionary PDEs.
Preference will be given to candidates who can connect to existing research strengths in the department. The preferred starting date is 1 September 2021, or before. The department has a strong desire to hire more female colleagues. Therefore, women are especially encouraged to apply.</description></item><item><title>18th School on interactions between Dynamical Systems and Partial Differential Equations, June 28–July 2, 2021</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/12/18th-school-on-interactions-between-dynamical-systems-and-partial-differential-equations-jisd2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 17:45:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/12/18th-school-on-interactions-between-dynamical-systems-and-partial-differential-equations-jisd2021/</guid><description>18th School on interactions between Dynamical Systems and Partial Differential Equations (JISD2021)
June 28 – July 2, 2021
Centre de Recerca Matemàtica
The JISD is an annual meeting between experts and young researchers in Dynamical Systems and Partial Differential Equations (PDEs). It is designed to encourage and enhance exchange of knowledge and methods, with the goal of advancing the study of cutting-edge problems in the aforesaid fields of mathematics and with the aim of fostering the interaction among the participants.</description></item><item><title>Semester Dynamics, Transfer Operators, and Spectra, Lausanne, January-June 2021</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/12/semester-dynamics-transfer-operators-and-spectra-lausanne-january-june-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 15:00:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/12/semester-dynamics-transfer-operators-and-spectra-lausanne-january-june-2021/</guid><description>Update regarding the semester Dynamics, Transfer Operators, and Spectra, at CIB, EPFL, Lausanne, January-June 2021.
The conference Linear Response: Rigorous Results and Applications (25-29 January 2021) and the Bernoulli lecture by Lai-Sang Young (28 January 2021) will be fully online.
Registration is required, the deadline is 8 January 2021.
The modalities (fully online, hybrid, or fully in-person) of the other scheduled events will be decided later, depending on the Covid situation.</description></item><item><title>Third DAI Day goes online: New dates and website announcement</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/12/third-dai-day-goes-online-new-dates-and-website-announcement/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 09:37:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/12/third-dai-day-goes-online-new-dates-and-website-announcement/</guid><description>Due to the current Covid-related restrictions in Italy, the Third DinAmicI Day (also abbreviated 3rd DAI Day) will take place online. It will also be split into two afternoons, December 17 and 18, 2020, instead of a single full day, as previously announced.
A website with the program of the event and all related information (including a link to download the poster) is up: http://daiday2020.unisalento.it
See you all online!</description></item><item><title>Another postdoc in Paris</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/11/post-doctoral-position-in-paris-in-dynamical-systems/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 18:52:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/11/post-doctoral-position-in-paris-in-dynamical-systems/</guid><description>The Institut de Mathématiques de Jussieu-Paris Rive Gauche will offer one post-doctoral position in the field of in the field of differentiable dynamical systems (bifurcation theory, parameter selection, hyperbolicity, fractal geometry) starting September 1, 2021.
This is a two-year post-doctoral position funded by the European Research Council (PI: Pierre Berger) via the French CNRS.
No teaching requirements for this position. The starting date of is flexible. The salary is approximately 3000 euros/month before taxes.</description></item><item><title>Postdocs at Scuola Normale Superiore, Pisa</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/11/postdocs-at-scuola-normale-superiore-pisa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 08:19:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/11/postdocs-at-scuola-normale-superiore-pisa/</guid><description>The Scuola Normale Superiore announces a selection for 5 post-doc research positions named “Junior Visiting Positions”. The positions will concern the following subject matters:
Position no. 1: Algebraic Geometry and/or Number Theory;
Position no. 2: Topology, Differential Geometry and/or Geometric Analysis;
Position no. 3: Partial Differential Equations and/or Probability;
Position no. 4: Numerical Analysis and/or Financial Mathematics;
Position no. 5: Dynamical Systems, as part of the research project “Dynamics and Information Research Institute - Quantum Information (Teoria dell&amp;rsquo;Informazione), Quantum Technologies” (Addendum 2019 Convenzione 2014 Scuola-Unicredit).</description></item><item><title>Postdoc position in Paris</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/11/postdoc-position-in-paris/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 21:20:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/11/postdoc-position-in-paris/</guid><description>The Institut de Mathématiques de Jussieu-Paris Rive Gauche will offer one post-doctoral position in the field of symplectic/contact topology and dynamics starting September 1, 2021.
This is a two-year post-doctoral position funded by the European Research Council via the French CNRS.
No teaching requirements for this position. The starting date of is flexible. The salary is approximately 3000 euros/month before taxes. A grant of 3500 euros per year for research related travel expenses will be provided.</description></item><item><title>Anna Miriam Benini (Università di Parma, Italy)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/miriam-benini-universita-di-parma-italy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 14:07:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/miriam-benini-universita-di-parma-italy/</guid><description>Speaker: Anna Miriam Benini (Università di Parma, Italy)
Title: Infinite entropy for transcendental entire functions
*Abstract: * Defining entropy on noncompact metric spaces is a tricky business, since there are several natural and nonequivalent generalizations of the usual notions of entropy for continuous maps on compact spaces. By defining entropy for transcendental maps on the complex plane as the sup over the entropy restricted to compact forward invariant subsets, we prove that with this definition the entropy of such functions is infinite.</description></item><item><title>Isaia Nisoli (Universidade Federal do Rio de Janeiro, Brazil)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/isaia-nisoli-universidade-federal-de-rio-de-janeiro-brazil/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 15:00:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/isaia-nisoli-universidade-federal-de-rio-de-janeiro-brazil/</guid><description>Speaker: Isaia Nisoli (Universidade Federal do Rio de Janeiro, Brazil)
Title: A simple system presenting Noise Induced Order
Abstract: In this talk I will present a family of one dimensional systems with random additive noise such that, as the noise size increases, the Lyapunov exponent of the stationary measure transitions from positive to negative. This phenomena is known in literature as Noise Induced Order, and was first observed in a model of the Belosouv-Zhabotinsky reaction and its existence was proven only recently by Galatolo-Monge-Nisoli.</description></item><item><title>Postdoc at Northumbria University Newcastle</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/11/postdoc-at-northumbria-university-newcastle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 13:40:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/11/postdoc-at-northumbria-university-newcastle/</guid><description>A 12-month postdoctoral research position in Mathematics is now open within the MCNP (Mathematics of Complex and Nonlinear Phenomena) group in the Department of Mathematics, Physics and Electrical Engineering Northumbria University Newcastle. Please note: This position had been already advertised in July 2020, but following a major IT incident it has not been possible to access information about applications submitted for this post. Sincere apologies to all applicants who will possibly read this email and whose application happened to be not accessible.</description></item><item><title>Carlangelo Liverani (Università di Roma Tor Vergata, Italy)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/carlangelo-liverani-universita-di-roma-tor-vergata-italy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 13:58:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/carlangelo-liverani-universita-di-roma-tor-vergata-italy/</guid><description>Speaker: Carlangelo Liverani (Università di Roma Tor Vergata, Italy)
Title: Locating Ruelle-Pollicott resonances
Abstract: We study the spectrum of transfer operators associated to various dynamical systems. Our aim is to obtain precise information on discrete spectrum. To this end we propose a unitary approach. We consider various settings where new information can be obtained following different branches along the proposed path. These settings include affine expanding Markov maps, uniformly expanding Markov maps, non-uniformly expanding maps, hyperbolic diffeomorphisms.</description></item><item><title>PhD position in Bremen</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/11/phd-position-in-bremen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 18:00:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/11/phd-position-in-bremen/</guid><description>Prof. Anke Paul at the University of Bremen advertises a position for a doctoral researcher (a.k.a. Ph.D. student), starting April 2021 or later. The position is a standard university position (proper employment, E 13 TV-L, 50%), fixed for 3 years. It comes with very light teaching duties.
In interested, please email apohl@uni-bremen.de.</description></item><item><title>MSCA PhD position in Munich</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/11/msca-phd-position-in-munich/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 22:44:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/11/msca-phd-position-in-munich/</guid><description>The research group on Multiscale and Stochastic Dynamics at the Technical University of Munich, coordinated by Prof. Christian Kuehn, seeks candidates for a 3-year doctoral researcher position within the newly funded MSCA ITN CriticalEarth.
Interested candidates should have a background in at least one of the following areas: Dynamical Systems, Stochastic Processes, Scientific Computing or PDE.
The main application deadline is January 31st 2021, though evaluation of applications may start immediately.</description></item><item><title>Stefano Marò (Università di Pisa, Italy)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/stefano-maro-university-of-pisa-italy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 21:29:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/stefano-maro-university-of-pisa-italy/</guid><description>Speaker: Stefano Marò (Università di Pisa, Italy)
Title: Chaotic motion in the breathing circle billiard
Abstract: We consider the free motion of a point particle inside a circular billiard with periodically moving boundary, with the assumption that the collisions of the particle with the boundary are elastic so that the energy of the particle is not preserved. It is known that if the motion of the boundary is regular enough then the energy is bounded due to the existence of invariant curves.</description></item><item><title>Postdocs in Bologna</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/10/postdocs-in-bologna-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 13:25:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/10/postdocs-in-bologna-3/</guid><description>The Department of Mathematics of Università di Bologna has opened a call for two 1-year postdoctoral positions denominated “Starting postdoctoral position in Mathematics and Applications in Sciences, Social Sciences and Engineering”.
The positions are open to all candidates who hold a Ph.D. in Mathematics, Physics, Computer Science, Engineering, Statistics or Economics, with a preference for applicants who have obtained their Ph.D.’s in recent years. They are “open” positions in that all research areas that are currently represented in the Department will be considered (see the announcement for a list of them).</description></item><item><title>DAI Seminar, previous editions</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminar-previous-editions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 09:24:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminar-previous-editions/</guid><description>This page contains a record of the past editions of the
DinAmicI: Another Internet Seminar
(a.k.a. DAI Seminar)
a series of online seminars on Dynamical Systems and their applications.
Most seminars can be replayed on the DinAmicI YouTube Channel.
Organizers: A. Bianchi, C. Bonanno, M. Lenci, M. Seri, A. Sorrentino
May 14, 2020, 5pm CET: Giulio Tiozzo (University of Toronto, Canada), Central limit theorems for counting measures in coarse negative curvature May 21, 2020, 5pm CET: Martin Leguil (Université Paris-Sud 11, France), ***Some rigidity results for billiards and hyperbolic flows *** May 28, 2020, 5pm CET: Francesco Cellarosi (Queen&amp;rsquo;s University, Canada), Rational Horocycle lifts and the tails of Quadratic Weyl sums June 4, 2020, 5pm CET: Sandro Vaienti (Centre de Physique Théorique, Marseille, France), Thermodynamic formalism for random weighted covering systems June 10, 2020, 5pm CET: Seminar by Marta Maggioni postponed #ShutDownSTEM June 17, 2020, 5pm CET: Sunrose Shrestha (Tufts University, USA), The topology and geometry of random square-tiled surfaces June 24, 2020, 5pm CET: Andreas Knauf (Friedrich-Alexander-Universität Erlangen-Nürnberg, Germany), Asymptotic velocity for scattering particles July 1, 2020, 5pm CET: Marta Maggioni (Universiteit Leiden, Netherlands), Matching for random systems with an application to minimal weight expansions July 8, 2020, 5pm CET: Françoise Pène (Université de Bretagne Occidentale, France), * Invariance by induction of the asymptotic variance*</description></item><item><title>Conference "Weak KAM theory - XXV years later", Avignon, May 31 - June 4, 2021</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/10/conference-weak-kam-theory-xxv-years-later-avignon-may-31-june-4-2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 10:46:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/10/conference-weak-kam-theory-xxv-years-later-avignon-may-31-june-4-2021/</guid><description>International conference
Weak KAM theory - XXV years later
Avignon Université, France
May 31 - June 4, 2021
All info here: http://perso.ens-lyon.fr/marco.mazzucchelli/Weak_KAM_XXV/?fbclid=IwAR0MDzTiWSjfaPgZPGxQF6iNtFCd_ud7cQi4_UvSPPLLRaaZOrIUmWmdFaE</description></item><item><title>Postdoc and Junior Professorship in Geometry and Dynamics at Heidelberg University</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/10/post-doc-and-junior-professorship-in-geometry-and-dynamics-at-heidelberg-university/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 10:02:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/10/post-doc-and-junior-professorship-in-geometry-and-dynamics-at-heidelberg-university/</guid><description>Postdoc position
The Department of Mathematics at Heidelberg University invites applications for one or more postdoctoral positions in mathematics within the newly founded Research Station Geometry and Dynamics at the Mathematical Institute of Heidelberg University, starting in the fall of 2021. The duration of the appointment is 2 years with a possible extension for a third year if funding is available.
https://www.mathjobs.org/jobs/list/16551
The research station bundles fundamental research activities in geometry and dynamical systems and promotes interaction of these fields with other science, as well as with society.</description></item><item><title>PhD positions at RWTH Aachen (Germany)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/10/ph-d-positions-at-rwth-aachen-germany/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 11:05:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/10/ph-d-positions-at-rwth-aachen-germany/</guid><description>The DFG via the Research Training Group “Energy, Entropy, and Dissipative Dynamics” (EDDy) at RWTH Aachen advertises the opening of several doctoral positions.
There are several projects available in a wide range of topics, including Symplectic Dynamics.
For more details please visit: https://www.eddy.rwth-aachen.de/</description></item><item><title>Postdoc positions at IST Austria</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/10/postdoc-positions-at-ist-austria/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 12:38:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/10/postdoc-positions-at-ist-austria/</guid><description>Postdoc positions are open at IST Austria with low teaching and good research opportunities.
The deadline for application is January 15, 2021. The starting date is negotiable.
Info: https://ist.ac.at/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/2020_09_Postdoc-Kaloshin-Group_Deadline-15.1.2021.pdf</description></item><item><title>Third DAI DAY - save the date</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/10/third-dai-day-save-the-date/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 08:52:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/10/third-dai-day-save-the-date/</guid><description>Dear DinAmicI,
We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce that the next DAI DAY will take place on December 5, 2020 in Lecce.
It is a tremendous occasion for you to attend dynamical seminars and the scientific assembly of the group, and to spend a weekend in a beautiful city.
We hope to see you all in Lecce, but in the difficult times we all are living, the event will also be streamed.</description></item><item><title>PhD Course in Padua (via zoom): Introduction to Floer Homology</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/09/ph-d-course-in-padua-via-zoom-introduction-to-floer-homology/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 08:18:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/09/ph-d-course-in-padua-via-zoom-introduction-to-floer-homology/</guid><description>Title of the course: &amp;ldquo;Introduction to Floer Homology&amp;rdquo;
Lecturer: Marco Mazzucchelli (CNRS &amp;amp; ENS Lyon)
Syllabus:
Lecture 1: Crash course in algebraic topology: singular homology and cohomology, DeRham cohomology.
Lecture 2: The Morse homology theorem.
Lecture 3: Variational principle for Hamiltonian periodic orbits, action spectrum, the Conley-Zehnder index.
Lecture 4: Construction of the Floer homology groups for aspherical manifolds I.
Lecture 5: Construction of the Floer homology groups for aspherical manifolds II, proof of the Arnold conjecture on the fixed points of generic Hamiltonian diffeomorphisms.</description></item><item><title>Tenure Track Assistant Professor in Dynamical Systems at EPFL Lausanne</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/08/tenure-track-assistant-professor-in-dynamical-systems-at-epfl-lausanne/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 16:21:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/08/tenure-track-assistant-professor-in-dynamical-systems-at-epfl-lausanne/</guid><description>The School of Basic Sciences (Physics, Chemistry and Mathematics) at EPFL -Lausanne seeks to appoint a Tenure Track Assistant Professor of Mathematics with research interests in the theory of dynamical systems, broadly construed. Indicative areas of interest include, but are not limited to: algebraic/analytical dynamics, dynamics and geometry, ergodic theory, locally homogeneous spaces.
https://www.epfl.ch/about/working/faculty-position-in-mathematics/
Applications should be uploaded (as PDFs) by** September 30, 2020 **to
https://facultyrecruiting.epfl.ch/positiondetails/23691270
Enquiries may be addressed to:</description></item><item><title>Il Gruppo UMI DinAmicI è realtà!</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/08/il-gruppo-umi-dinamici-e-realta/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 08:27:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/08/il-gruppo-umi-dinamici-e-realta/</guid><description>Abbiamo appreso che la Commissione Scientifica dell&amp;rsquo;UMI ha approvato la nostra richiesta di creazione del Gruppo UMI proposto dai DinAmicI. L&amp;rsquo;inizio ufficiale delle attività del gruppo è fissato a giorno 1 settembre.
Il primo passo sarà l&amp;rsquo;elezione degli organi ufficiali del gruppo, le elezioni saranno indette dal Presidente dell&amp;rsquo;UMI nei prossimi mesi. Vi faremo sapere!
The Italian Mathematical Union has recently approved our application for the creation of &amp;ldquo;Gruppo UMI DinAmicI&amp;rdquo;, a unit inside the Union.</description></item><item><title>PhD and postdoc positions at Bath and Utrecht</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/07/phd-positions-at-the-university-of-bath-and-at-the-university-of-utrecht/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 12:31:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/07/phd-positions-at-the-university-of-bath-and-at-the-university-of-utrecht/</guid><description>A PhD position in the semiclassical theory of subelliptic operators is being advertised at the University of Bath (UK). The prospective advisor is Véronique Fischer. The student will be part of the project titled &amp;ldquo;Quantum Limits for sub-elliptic operators&amp;quot;:
https://www.findaphd.com/phds/project/quantum-limits-for-sub-elliptic-operators/?p122901
As part of the same project there is also a call for Postdoc (Research Associate): https://www.bath.ac.uk/jobs/Vacancy.aspx?ref=CC7693
The deadline for both applications is Sunday, September 13, 2020.
Another position is being advertised in contact and symplectic topology at the University of Utrecht (NL).</description></item><item><title>Call for PhD and professor in Dynamical Systems at the University of Groningen</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/07/call-for-phd-and-professor-in-dynamical-systems-at-the-university-of-groningen/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 09:57:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/07/call-for-phd-and-professor-in-dynamical-systems-at-the-university-of-groningen/</guid><description>The Bernoulli Institute of the University of Groningen (NL) is advertising a 4-year PhD position in dynamical systems, to work on the combination of multi-timescale dynamical systems and networks. The application deadline is August 31, for more information please refer to https://www.rug.nl/about-ug/work-with-us/job-opportunities/?details=00347-02S0007TEP
There is also a call for an Assistant Professor (tenure track) or (preferably) Associate Professor, with a strong track record in Dynamical Systems. The deadline for the application is August 16.</description></item><item><title>RTD-A (non-tenure-track 3-year position) in Mathematical Physics in Milan</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/07/rtd-a-non-tenure-track-3-year-position-in-mathematical-physics-in-milan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 08:03:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/07/rtd-a-non-tenure-track-3-year-position-in-mathematical-physics-in-milan/</guid><description>A Ricercatore di tipo A (non-tenure-track 3 year) position in Mathematical Physics (S.C. 01/A4, SSD MAT/07) has been announced at Università degli Studi di Milano.
Deadline: 15 July 2020
Info and application form: https://www.unimi.it/it/ateneo/lavora-con-noi/reclutamento-ricercatori/selezioni-ricercatori/ricercatore-tipo-sc-01/a4-ssd-mat/07-codice-4390</description></item><item><title>Tenure Track Assistant or Associate Professor in Dynamical Systems at Groningen</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/06/tenure-track-assistant-or-associate-professor-in-dynamical-systems-at-groningen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 08:37:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/06/tenure-track-assistant-or-associate-professor-in-dynamical-systems-at-groningen/</guid><description>The University of Groningen is looking for an Assistant Professor (tenure track) or (preferably) Associate Professor, depending on your profile (see The University of Groningen Career Paths in Science), with a strong track record in Dynamical Systems.
Deadline for application: 16 August 2020
All info at https://www.rug.nl/about-ug/work-with-us/job-opportunities/?details=00347-02S0007RTP&amp;amp;dept=fse
Note that in nearly all Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s and Master&amp;rsquo;s degree programmes at the Faculty of Science and Engineering of the University of Groningen teaching is done in English.</description></item><item><title>Call for expression of interest, Rome Tor Vergata</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/06/call-for-expression-of-interest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 19:35:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/06/call-for-expression-of-interest/</guid><description>**Call for expression of interest ** (Dept. of Mathematics, Univ. Rome Tor Vergata)
The Department of Mathematics at the University of Rome Tor Vergata invites expressions of interest for Senior (Tenure-Track) Assistant Professor (&amp;lsquo;RTD-B&amp;rsquo;) and Tenured Associate Professor positions in the following area of Pure and Applied Mathematics:
a) Data Analysis, Statistics and Machine Learning;
b) Historical and pedagogical aspects of mathematics;
c) Numerical optimization with special focus on big data and machine learning applications.</description></item><item><title>Françoise Pène (Université de Bretagne Occidentale, France)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/francoise-pene-universite-de-bretagne-occidentale-france/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 11:00:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/francoise-pene-universite-de-bretagne-occidentale-france/</guid><description>Speaker: Françoise Pène (Université de Bretagne Occidentale, France)
Title: Invariance by induction of the asymptotic variance
Abstract: It is well known that the integral of an observable is preserved by induction. We are interested here in extensions of this result to moments of order 2 and 3. We have two natural candidates for the second and third order moments: the classical asymptotic variance (given by the Green-Kubo formula) and an analogous quantity of the third order.</description></item><item><title>Andreas Knauf (Friedrich-Alexander-Universität Erlangen-Nürnberg, Germany)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/andreas-knauf-friedrich-alexander-universitat-erlangen-nurnberg-germany/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 07:07:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/andreas-knauf-friedrich-alexander-universitat-erlangen-nurnberg-germany/</guid><description>Speaker: Andreas Knauf (Friedrich-Alexander-Universität Erlangen-Nürnberg, Germany)
Title: Asymptotic velocity for scattering particles
*Abstract: *Partly with Jacques Fejoz, Richard Montgomery, Stefan Fleischer and Manuel Quaschner.
The past and future of scattering particle systems is partly determined by their asymptotic velocity, that is, the Cesàro limit of the velocity. That this exists for bounded interactions and all initial conditions, is part of a statement sometimes called &amp;lsquo;asymptotic completeness&amp;rsquo;. The same statement does not apply to individual initial conditions in celestial mechanics.</description></item><item><title>Seminar by Marta Maggioni postponed to July 1</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/seminar-by-marta-maggioni-universiteit-leiden-netherlands-postponed-to-july-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 08:34:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/seminar-by-marta-maggioni-universiteit-leiden-netherlands-postponed-to-july-1/</guid><description>The DinAmicI, in solidarity with the #Strike4BlackLives and #ShutDownSTEM movements on June 10, 2020, acknowledge the racism present throughout academia and especially in STEM subjects. In agreement with our speaker Marta Maggioni, whom we sincerely thank, we have decided to reschedule her talk to July 1st. We apologize for any inconvenience and invite everybody to reflect and take action on systemic inequalities in academia and science.
https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-020-01721-x</description></item><item><title>School "Modern Aspects of Dynamical Systems" officially postponed</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/06/school-modern-aspects-of-dynamical-systems-officially-postponed/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 08:11:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/06/school-modern-aspects-of-dynamical-systems-officially-postponed/</guid><description>The school
&amp;ldquo;Modern Aspects of Dynamical Systems&amp;rdquo;
organized by Fondazione CIME to be held in Cetraro (Cosenza, Italy) at Grand Hotel San Michele, (see the first announcement here) has now been officially postponed to next year.
The new dates are August 2-7, 2021. Procedures for the applications will be decided and communicated by Fondazione CIME.
For more information please contact one of the directors: Claudio Bonanno (Università di Pisa), Alfonso Sorrentino (Università di Roma “Tor Vergata”) and Corinna Ulcigrai (Universität Zürich).</description></item><item><title>Sunrose Shrestha (Tufts University, USA)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/sunrose-shrestha-tufts-university-usa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 13:29:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/sunrose-shrestha-tufts-university-usa/</guid><description>Speaker: Sunrose Shrestha (Tufts University, USA)
Title: The topology and geometry of random square-tiled surfaces
Abstract: A square-tiled surface (STS) is a branched cover of the standard square torus with branching over exactly one point. They are concrete examples of translation surfaces which are an important class of singular flat metrics on 2-manifolds with applications in Teichmüller theory and polygonal billiards. In this talk we will consider a randomizing model for STSs based on permutation pairs and use it to compute the genus distribution.</description></item><item><title>May-12 online event: Celebrating Women in Math (9 June 2020, 15:00)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/05/may-12-online-event-celebrating-women-in-math-9-june-2020-1500/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 10:16:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/05/may-12-online-event-celebrating-women-in-math-9-june-2020-1500/</guid><description>The Department of Mathematics of University of Rome Tor Vergata invites you to attend the following event, organized as part of the international project &amp;ldquo;May 12&amp;rdquo; (https://may12.womeninmaths.org/).
Lecture in honour of Maryam Mirzakhani:
Speaker: Lucia Caporaso (Roma Tre University)
Title: Varieties of Varieties after Mirzakhani.
Date: 9 Giugno 2020, ore 15
Web page (on which it will be posted the link for the streaming): http://www.mat.uniroma2.it/may12.php
The lecture will be followed by the screening of the documentary film : “Secrets of the surface: the mathematical vision of Maryam Mirzakhani” by George Csicsery.</description></item><item><title>Marta Maggioni (Universiteit Leiden, Netherlands)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/marta-maggioni-universiteit-leiden-netherlands/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 19:31:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/marta-maggioni-universiteit-leiden-netherlands/</guid><description>Speaker: **Marta Maggioni ** (Universiteit Leiden, Netherlands)
Title: Matching for random systems with an application to minimal weight expansions
Abstract: We consider families of skew-product maps, representing systems evolving in discrete time in which, at each time step, one of a number of transformations is chosen according to an i.i.d process and applied. We extend the notion of matching for such dynamical systems and we show that, for a certain family of piecewise affine random maps of the interval, the property of random matching implies that any invariant density is piecewise constant.</description></item><item><title>Recruitment in Ergodic Theory &amp; Dynamical Systems at University of Warwick</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/05/recruitment-in-ergodic-theory-dynamical-systems-at-university-of-warwick/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 07:15:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/05/recruitment-in-ergodic-theory-dynamical-systems-at-university-of-warwick/</guid><description>Prof. Mark Pollicott (University of Warwick) advertises the following positions in the area of Ergodic theory and Dynamical Systems:
a phD studentship (funded for up to 4 years); 3 year Post doctoral position; For more information, contact:
Mark Poliicott masdbl@warwick.ac.uk</description></item><item><title>DAI Seminar</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 12:29:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminar/</guid><description>Welcome to the page of the
DinAmicI: Another Internet Seminar
(a.k.a. DAI Seminar)
a series of online seminars on Dynamical Systems and their applications. Starting from November 2020 the seminar will run biweekly (mostly) on Thursday afternoons at 4pm Central European Time.
Organizers: A. Bianchi, C. Bonanno, M. Lenci, M. Seri, A. Sorrentino
Recent and upcoming seminars:
(click on a date to be directed to that seminar&amp;rsquo;s event page, showing all details of the seminar, including the link to the Zoom room and buttons to add the event to your electronic calendars)</description></item><item><title>Sandro Vaienti (Centre de Physique Théorique, Marseille, France)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/sandro-vaienti-centre-de-physique-theorique-marseille-france/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 12:24:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/sandro-vaienti-centre-de-physique-theorique-marseille-france/</guid><description>Speaker: **Sandro Vaienti ** (Centre de Physique Théorique, Marseille, France)
Title: Thermodynamic formalism for random weighted covering systems
Abstract: We develop a quenched thermodynamic formalism for random dynamical systems generated by countably branched, piecewise-monotone mappings of the interval that satisfy a random covering condition.
Joint with J. Atnip, G. Froyland and C. Gonzalez-Tokman</description></item><item><title>Francesco Cellarosi (Queen's University, Canada)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/28-5-francesco-cellarosi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 12:22:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/28-5-francesco-cellarosi/</guid><description>Speaker: Francesco Cellarosi (Queen&amp;rsquo;s University, Canada)
Title: Rational Horocycle lifts and the tails of Quadratic Weyl sums
Abstract: Equidistribution of horocycles on hyperbolic surfaces has been used to dynamically answer several probabilistic questions about number-theoretical objects. In this talk we focus on horocycle lifts, i.e. curves on higher-dimensional manifolds whose projection to the hyperbolic surface is a classical horocycle, and their behaviour under the action of the geodesic flow. It is known that when such horocycle lifts are `generic’, then their push forward via the geodesic flow becomes equidistributed in the ambient manifold.</description></item><item><title>Martin Leguil (Université Paris-Sud 11, France)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/martin-leguil-universite-paris-sud-11-france/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 12:20:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/martin-leguil-universite-paris-sud-11-france/</guid><description>Speaker: Martin Leguil (Université Paris-Sud 11, France)
*Title: **Some rigidity results for billiards and hyperbolic flows ***
Abstract: In a project with P. Bálint, J. De Simoi and V. Kaloshin, we have been studying the inverse problem for a class of open dispersing billiards obtained by removing from the plane a finite number of smooth strictly convex scatterers satisfying a non-eclipse condition. The dynamics of such billiards is hyperbolic (Axiom A), and there is a natural labeling of periodic orbits.</description></item><item><title>Giulio Tiozzo (University of Toronto, Canada)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/giulio-tiozzo-university-of-toronto-canada/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 12:18:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/giulio-tiozzo-university-of-toronto-canada/</guid><description>Speaker: Giulio Tiozzo (University of Toronto, Canada)
Title: Central limit theorems for counting measures in coarse negative curvature
Abstract: We establish general central limit theorems for an action of a group on a hyperbolic space with respect to counting for the word length in the group.
In 2013, Chas, Li, and Maskit produced numerical experiments on random closed geodesics on a hyperbolic pair of pants. Namely, they drew uniformly at random conjugacy classes of a given word length, and considered the hyperbolic length of the corresponding closed geodesic on the pair of pants.</description></item><item><title>The Brin Prize 2020 awarded to Corinna Ulcigrai!</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/04/the-brin-prize-2020-to-corinna-ulcigrai/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 12:52:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/04/the-brin-prize-2020-to-corinna-ulcigrai/</guid><description>The ninth Brin Prize in Dynamical Systems has been awarded to our own
Corinna Ulcigrai (University of Zurich)
for her fundamental work on the ergodic theory of locally Hamiltonian flows on surfaces, of translation flows on periodic surfaces and wind-tree models, and her seminal work on higher genus generalizations of Markov and Lagrange spectra.
You can find the list of Corinna&amp;rsquo;s prize papers at https://math.psu.edu/dynsys/Brinprize or https://www-math.umd.edu/dynamics-conference.html
The award ceremony was planned for 18/04/2020 as part of the 2020 Maryland Spring dynamical systems conference, which has been canceled.</description></item><item><title>PhD scholarships at the university of Groningen</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/03/phd-scholarships-at-the-university-of-groningen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 21:51:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/03/phd-scholarships-at-the-university-of-groningen/</guid><description>There will be nine 4 year PhD position available at the University of Groningen.
Although the research projects are interdisciplinary and across mathematics, physics and astrophysics, at least two of the research topics (number 6 and 9 in the topics list) have a strong mathematical component, with focus on dynamical systems, hamiltonian mechanics and semiclassical analysis.
The advertisement is available at the following link: https://www.rug.nl/education/phd-programmes/phd-scholarship-programme/phd-scholarships?details=00347-02S0007L1P
The deadline for the application is 1 April 11:59 pm / before 2 April Dutch local time.</description></item><item><title>Two-year research fellowship at the University of Pisa</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/03/two-year-research-fellowship-at-the-university-of-pisa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 10:20:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/03/two-year-research-fellowship-at-the-university-of-pisa/</guid><description>Opening for a two-year research fellowship in Dynamical Systems at the University of Pisa. This position is supported by the national grant MIUR-PRIN 2017 “Regular and stochastic behaviour in dynamical systems“.
More information and the official call (with English version) can be found at: https://www.unipi.it/ateneo/bandi/assegni/2020/mat/02042020/index.htm
Applications should be received by April 2, 2020.
Please bring this announcement to the attention of people that could be interested.</description></item><item><title>Ph.D. course in Padova: Introduction to Floer Homology</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/01/ph-d-course-in-padova-introduction-to-floer-homology/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 16:27:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2020/01/ph-d-course-in-padova-introduction-to-floer-homology/</guid><description>Ph.D. Course in Padova
INTRODUCTION TO FLOER HOMOLOGY by Marco Mazzucchelli (ENS Lyon)
 https://www.math.unipd.it/~dottmath/corsi2020/Mazzucchelli.pdf First lecture: 28th February 2020
To register: https://dottorato.math.unipd.it/current-activity/courses</description></item><item><title>Postdoc position in Ergodic Theory and Dynamical Systems at University of Zurich</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/12/postdoc-position-in-ergodic-theory-and-dynamical-systems-at-university-of-zurich/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 12:06:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/12/postdoc-position-in-ergodic-theory-and-dynamical-systems-at-university-of-zurich/</guid><description>The position is for the period of 2 years, renewable to 3 years and can be started between March 1st, 2020 and September 1st, 2020 (negotiable). The successful candidate will be supported by Prof. Corinna Ulcigrai SNSF grant “Ergodic and spectral properties of surface flows”.
Deadline: January 5, 2020
For more information visit the website https://www.mathjobs.org/jobs/jobs/15253</description></item><item><title>Floer Postdoctoral Research Fellowship in Mathematics</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/12/floer-postdoctoral-research-fellowship-in-mathematics-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 18:11:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/12/floer-postdoctoral-research-fellowship-in-mathematics-2/</guid><description>The Floer Centre of Geometry (FCG) invites applications for a 3 year postdoctoral fellowship to pursue research in mathematics at the Ruhr-Universität Bochum.
They are looking for an outstanding, independent and highly motivated scholar with a strong research record in one of the fields covered by the FCG (see http://www.floer.rub.de/).
Payment is based on the German TVL-13 scale. The fellowship includes a research grant of 2000 € per year for conference travel support.</description></item><item><title>2-year research fellowship in Dynamical Systems at University of Rome Tor Vergata</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/12/2-year-research-fellowship-in-dynamical-systems-at-university-of-rome-tor-vergata/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 17:14:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/12/2-year-research-fellowship-in-dynamical-systems-at-university-of-rome-tor-vergata/</guid><description>Opening for a 2-year research fellowship in Dynamical Systems at University of Rome Tor Vergata. This position is supported by the national grant MIUR-PRIN 2017 &amp;ldquo;Regular and stochastic behaviour in dynamical systems&amp;rdquo;.
More information and on the website: https://web.uniroma2.it/module/name/Content/newlang/italiano/action/showpage/navpath/HOM/content_id/78913/section_id/4992
Applications should be received by 30/01/2020.
For further information, contact:
Oliver Butterley: butterley@mat.uniroma2.it Carlangelo Liverani: liverani@mat.uniroma2.it Alfonso Sorrentino: sorrentino@mat.uniroma2.it</description></item><item><title>School "Modern Aspects of Dynamical Systems" - registrations are now open</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/12/school-modern-aspects-of-dynamical-systems-registrations-are-now-open/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 09:22:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/12/school-modern-aspects-of-dynamical-systems-registrations-are-now-open/</guid><description>This is to announce that registrations to the Fondazione CIME school &amp;ldquo;Modern Aspects of Dynamical Systems&amp;rdquo;, 20-24 July 2020, are now open until April 30th, 2020.
Here it is the first announcement of the school with more information.
To register please apply on the website http://web.math.unifi.it/users/cime/</description></item><item><title>RTD di tipo A (non-tenure track) in Fisica Matematica, Università di Pisa</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/11/rtd-di-tipo-a-non-tenure-track-in-fisica-matematica-universita-di-pisa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 17:22:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/11/rtd-di-tipo-a-non-tenure-track-in-fisica-matematica-universita-di-pisa/</guid><description>E` stato pubblicato sul sito web dell’Università di Pisa, il seguente bando per ricercatore a tempo determinato di tipo A (non-tenure track position)
https://alboufficiale.unipi.it/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/bando-prot-18.pdf
per il conferimento di n. 1 posto da ricercatore a tempo determinato Settore concorsuale 01/A4
SSD: MAT/07
Scadenza: 30 dicembre 2019, ore 13:00</description></item><item><title>School "Modern Aspects of Dynamical Systems" - 20-24 July 2020</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/11/school-modern-aspects-of-dynamical-systems-20-24-july-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 11:00:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/11/school-modern-aspects-of-dynamical-systems-20-24-july-2020/</guid><description>This is the first announcement of the school
&amp;ldquo;Modern Aspects of Dynamical Systems&amp;rdquo;
organized by Fondazione CIME to be held in Cetraro (Cosenza, Italy) in the period 20-24 July 2020. The venue of the school will be Grand Hotel San Michele.
The school is directed by Claudio Bonanno (Università di Pisa), Alfonso Sorrentino (Università di Roma &amp;ldquo;Tor Vergata&amp;rdquo;) and Corinna Ulcigrai (Universität Zürich).
The school will consist of the following courses:</description></item><item><title>4 postdoc positions in Lyon and Saint-Etienne</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/11/4-post-doc-positions-in-lyon-and-saint-etienne/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 18:15:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/11/4-post-doc-positions-in-lyon-and-saint-etienne/</guid><description>The Excellence Laboratory Milyon (Labex Milyon) has an opening for four postdoctoral positions in Lyon and Saint-Etienne, France, in the fields of Mathematics, Computer Science and their interactions (including some aspects of theoretical physics). Each position is for two years with no teaching load.
More information on the link below:
https://milyon.universite-lyon.fr/postdoctoral-positions-2020-2022--130160.kjsp?RH=1571748911317
Application deadline: January 7, 2020.</description></item><item><title>Winter school: Implicit Function Theorems in Geometry and Dynamics</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/11/winter-school-implicit-function-theorems-in-geometry-and-dynamics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 13:58:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/11/winter-school-implicit-function-theorems-in-geometry-and-dynamics/</guid><description>Announcement of the Winter School:
&amp;ldquo;Implicit function theorems in Geometry and Dynamics&amp;rdquo;
which will take place on
February 19 - 22, 2020
at Schloss Rauischholzhausen, a castle which is the congress hotel of the University of Gießen http://schloss.faber-management.de/.
The aim of the school is to present to master and PhD students two incarnations of the implicit function theorem that have strong influences on contemporary research, namely the implicit function theorem of Nash and Moser, and the implicit function theorem in scale calculus and polyfold-theory as developed by Hofer, Wysocki and Zehnder.</description></item><item><title>RTDb settore 01/A4 (Fisica Matematica) - Università di Roma "Tor Vergata"</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/10/rtdb-settore-01-a4-fisica-matematica-univ-roma-tor-vergata/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 19:13:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/10/rtdb-settore-01-a4-fisica-matematica-univ-roma-tor-vergata/</guid><description>Selezione pubblica per il reclutamento di n. 1 ricercatore con contratto a tempo determinato ai sensi dell’art. 24, comma 3, lettera b) della legge 30 dicembre 2010, n. 240 presso il Dipartimento di Matematica dell’Università degli Studi di Roma “Tor Vergata” per il settore concorsuale 01/A4 e settore scientifico disciplinare MAT/07 (Dipartimento di Eccellenza).
D.R. n. 2373 del 07/10/2019 (Rif. 1524) G.U. n. 86 del 29/10/2019
Scadenza 28/11/2019
http://web.uniroma2.it/module/name/Content/newlang/italiano/action/showpage/navpath/CON/content_id/77629/section_id/6206?fbclid=IwAR0Lf711HeDBWw43euDkz8S8ts3UDgP41P5tvCMlrUTFuK9UZoraN6yuLPA</description></item><item><title>PhD position at the University of Vienna</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/10/phd-position-at-the-university-of-vienna/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 19:11:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/10/phd-position-at-the-university-of-vienna/</guid><description>There will be a four year PhD position available at the University of Vienna.
The research topic will be ergodic properties of minimal Cantor systems, and the advertisement is available at the link below
https://univis.univie.ac.at/ausschreibungstellensuche/flow/bew_ausschreibung-flow?_flowExecutionKey=_c7A6BAEC5-25A7-FD27-D03D-9FFB070B8DCA_k91DC659A-BC0E-218D-AC13-1C5EA48FCD05&amp;amp;tid=74559.28
The application deadline is November 11.</description></item><item><title>Post-doctoral position in Paris in Symplectic/Contact Topology/Dynamics</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/10/post-doctoral-position-in-paris-in-symplectic-contact-topology-dynamics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 14:27:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/10/post-doctoral-position-in-paris-in-symplectic-contact-topology-dynamics/</guid><description>The Institut de Mathématiques de Jussieu-Paris Rive Gauche will offer one post-doctoral position in the field of symplectic/contact topology and dynamics starting September 1, 2020.
See: https://webusers.imj-prg.fr/~sobhan.seyfaddini/ERC_postdoc/ERC_postdoc.html
This is a two-year post-doctoral position funded by the European Research Council via the French CNRS.
No teaching requirements for this position. The starting date of is flexible. The salary is approximately 3000 euros/month before taxes. A grant of 3500 euros per year for research related travel expenses will be provided.</description></item><item><title>Postdoc position at Bar-Ilan University</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/08/postdoc-position-at-bar-ilan-university/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 08:54:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/08/postdoc-position-at-bar-ilan-university/</guid><description>There is a postdoc position in Ergodic Theory/Fractal Geometry available at Bar-Ilan University, Tel Aviv.
For more information look at
http://u.math.biu.ac.il/~solomyb/postdoc.html</description></item><item><title>PhD Studentships in Reading, UK</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/06/phd-studentships-in-reading-uk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 16:42:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/06/phd-studentships-in-reading-uk/</guid><description>PhD Studentships in the Mathematics of Planet Earth - starting in October 2019
Full Time 3 year PhD - Reading UK
Applications are sought for fully funded 3-year PhD studentships starting in October 2019 in the Centre for the Mathematics of Planet Earth www.reading.ac.uk/maths-and-stats/research/mathematics-of-planet-earth/Centre-for-the-Mathematics-of-Planet-Earth.aspx Applicants will have the opportunity to choose from available projects or develop a research project in consultation with a prospective supervisor in the following topics of mathematics with applications to weather, ocean and climate dynamics:</description></item><item><title>DinAmicI VI: Program available</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/05/dinamici-vi-program-available/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 10:36:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/05/dinamici-vi-program-available/</guid><description>Please visit the page
http://www.crm.sns.it/event/450/timetable.html#title
for the program of our upcoming workshop.
You can also download the poster of the workshop at http://www.crm.sns.it/media/event/450/posterA3v2-1.pdf
We hope to see you soon in Pisa.</description></item><item><title>Postdoc in Padova</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/05/postdoc-in-padova-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 08:43:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/05/postdoc-in-padova-2/</guid><description>Announcement for a 1-year postdoc position at Università di Padova:
Title of the project: Stable and Chaotic Motions in the Planetary Problem
Deadline for application: 20 May 2019
Info (in Italian) and application form (Italian and English): https://www.math.unipd.it/it/news/?id=2437</description></item><item><title>A tribute to Maryam Mirzakhani, Rome, 3 June 2019</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/05/a-tribute-to-maryam-mirzakhani-3-giugno-2019/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 07:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/05/a-tribute-to-maryam-mirzakhani-3-giugno-2019/</guid><description>The Department of Mathematics of Università di Roma &amp;ldquo;Tor Vergata&amp;rdquo;, in collaboration with Accademia dei Lincei, has organized a meeting in memory of Maryam Mirzakhani:
Speaker: Corinna Ulcigrai (University of Bristol &amp;amp; Universität Zürich).
Title: Billiards, Flat Surfaces and the Magic Wand Theorem.
Date: 3 June 2019, 16:00.
Place: Sala delle Scienze Fisiche, Accademia dei Lincei, Palazzo Corsini, Roma
This event is part of the international project &amp;ldquo;May 12&amp;rdquo; may12.womeninmaths.org and is supported by the MIUR grant &amp;ldquo;Dipartimento di eccellenza&amp;rdquo; (2018-2022), CUP E83C18000100006.</description></item><item><title>PhD Fellowships at GSSI, L'Aquila</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/04/phd-fellowships-at-gssi-laquila/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 16:36:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/04/phd-fellowships-at-gssi-laquila/</guid><description>The GSSI-Gran Sasso Science Institute offers 31 PhD fellowships for the academic year 2019/20 and invites applications for fellowships for the PhD Programmes in “Astroparticle Physics” (9), “Mathematics in Natural, Social and Life Sciences” (8), “Computer Science” (7), “Urban Studies and Regional Science”(7).
The official language for all PhD courses is English. The fellowships are awarded for 4 years and their yearly amount is € 16.159,91 gross. All PhD students have free accommodation at the GSSI facilities and use of the canteen.</description></item><item><title>DinAmicI VI: Website</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/04/dinamici-vi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 09:21:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/04/dinamici-vi/</guid><description>It is a pleasure to announce that the website of our next workshop is online.
Please visit the page http://www.crm.sns.it/event/450/</description></item><item><title>PhD studentship at Loughborough</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/03/phd-studentship-at-loughborough/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 22:15:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/03/phd-studentship-at-loughborough/</guid><description>A PhD studentship in Dynamical Systems is advertised at Loughborough.
The deadline to apply is 10 May 2019 and the starting date must be 1st of July 2019 (or few days later, if needed). To apply, follow the link:
https://www.lboro.ac.uk/study/postgraduate/research-degrees/funded/statistical-aspects-randomly-perturbed-dynamical/
Send any questions to w.bahsoun@lboro.ac.uk</description></item><item><title>DinAmicI VI: save the dates!</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/03/dinamici-vi-save-the-dates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 10:03:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/03/dinamici-vi-save-the-dates/</guid><description>The 6th edition of our beloved workshop, denominated with a spike of creativity
DinAmicI VI
will take place on
June 4-7, 2019
at the Centro di Ricerca Matematica Ennio De Giorgi,
Scuola Normale Superiore, Pisa.
A website with more info will appear soon and will be announced here. For the moment, save the dates!</description></item><item><title>Workshop "Ergodic Theory and Validated Dynamics", CIRM, Luminy, 8-12 July 2019</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/03/workshop-ergodic-theory-and-validated-dynamics-cirm-luminy-8-12-july-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 09:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/03/workshop-ergodic-theory-and-validated-dynamics-cirm-luminy-8-12-july-2019/</guid><description>Workshop
Ergodic Theory and Validated Dynamics
CIRM, Luminy, 8-12 July 2019
Expected participants include:
W. Bahsoun, O. Bandtlow, A.-H. Fan, J. Freitas, S. Galatolo, N. Haydn,
O. Jenkinson, M. Nicol, D. Ruelle, W. Tucker, H. Zhang.
Preregistration (by 15 April) is available at:
https://www.chairejeanmorlet.com/2019-2-pollicott-vaienti-2111.html
Organizers: M. Pollicott and S. Vaienti.</description></item><item><title>School "Modern Techniques in Smooth Ergodic Theory", CIRM, Luminy, 1-5 July 2019﻿</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/03/school-modern-techniques-in-smooth-ergodic-theory-cirm-luminy-1-5-july-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 09:38:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/03/school-modern-techniques-in-smooth-ergodic-theory-cirm-luminy-1-5-july-2019/</guid><description>School
Modern Techniques in Smooth Ergodic Theory
CIRM, Luminy, 1-5 July 2019
Courses will include:
*F. Faure and M. Tsujii, Micro-local methods in hyperbolic dynamics
*C. Liverani, Averaging and beyond for fast-slow hyperbolic systems
*F. Paulin, Rates of mixing for geodesic flows with Gibbs measures in negative curvature
and trees
*F. Rodriguez Hertz, Introduction to rigidity in hyperbolic dynamics
Preregistration (by 15 April) is available at:
https://www.chairejeanmorlet.com/2019-2-pollicott-vaienti-2110.html</description></item><item><title>2-year Postdoc positions and one PhD position at the RWTH Aachen University</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/03/2-year-postdoc-positions-and-one-phd-position-at-the-rwth-aachen-university/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 06:10:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/03/2-year-postdoc-positions-and-one-phd-position-at-the-rwth-aachen-university/</guid><description>Job openings to bring to the attention of potential candidates:
two 2-year Postdoc positions one PhD position  available at the RWTH Aachen University, starting June 2019, or within 6 months thereafter.
These are mostly research positions, with a teaching load consisting of exercise sections for undergraduate courses.
For the Postdoc positions, candidates are expected to conduct research in Symplectic/Contact Topology and/or Symplectic Dynamics, or Systolic Geometry.
The successful candidate for the PhD position will conduct research in Symplectic Dynamics, comprising the use of methods from Symplectic Geometry/Topology to study the global structure of Hamiltonian systems.</description></item><item><title>Research Fellow position at the University of St Andrews</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/02/research-fellow-position-at-the-university-of-st-andrews/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 09:14:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/02/research-fellow-position-at-the-university-of-st-andrews/</guid><description>This is to advertise a 22 month postdoctoral Research Fellow position at the University of St Andrews, commencing on August 1st 2019. The candidate will work with Kenneth Falconer and Jonathan Fraser on the EPSRC funded project Fourier analytic techniques in geometry and analysis. Please could you pass this information on to anyone you believe might be interested in applying for the position. The vacancy can be found here:
https://www.vacancies.st-andrews.ac.uk/Vacancies/W/1250/0/220432/889/research-fellow-in-analysis-ar1994as</description></item><item><title>Workshop "Thermodynamic Formalisms: Ergodic Theory and Geometry", Warwick, 22-26 July 2019</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/02/workshop-thermodynamic-formalisms-ergodic-theory-and-geometry-warwick-22-26-july-2019/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 17:16:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/02/workshop-thermodynamic-formalisms-ergodic-theory-and-geometry-warwick-22-26-july-2019/</guid><description>Workshop
&amp;ldquo;Thermodynamic Formalisms: Ergodic Theory and Geometry&amp;rdquo;
University of Warwick, 22-26 July 2019
(also celebrating the 60th birthday of Mark Pollicott)
The workshop webpage is at
https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/maths/research/events/2018-19/tfetg
including a link for registration. (Registration is free of charge but is required.)
Limited funding is available to support participants and applications for support can be made when registering. The deadline for applications and to request that the organisers arrange accommodation is 14 April 2019.</description></item><item><title>Conference "Equidistribution, invariant measures and applications: a tribute to the legacy of Marina Ratner", Jerusalem, May 19-24, 2019</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/02/conference-equidistribution-invariant-measures-and-applications-a-tribute-to-the-legacy-of-marina-ratner-jerusalem-may-19-24-2019/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 17:12:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/02/conference-equidistribution-invariant-measures-and-applications-a-tribute-to-the-legacy-of-marina-ratner-jerusalem-may-19-24-2019/</guid><description>Conference
&amp;ldquo;Equidistribution, invariant measures and applications: a tribute to the legacy of Marina Ratner&amp;rdquo;
Midrasha Mathematicae
Israel Institute for Advanced Study, Jerusalem, May 19-24, 2019
organized by Kostya Khanin, Elon Lindenstrauss, Jens Marklof, Yakov Pesin, Peter Sarnak
The meeting will include both research talks and short minicourses. Confirmed speakers include:
Yves Benoist (Orsay) Aaron Brown (University of Chicago) Dmitry Dolgopyat (University of Maryland) Manfred Einsiedler (ETH Zürich) Alex Eskin (The University of Chicago) Hillel Furstenberg (Hebrew University of Jerusalem) Adam Kanigowski (University of Maryland) Ilya Khayutin (Princeton University) Amos Nevo (Technion) Federico Rodriguez Hertz (Penn State University) Nimish Shah (The Ohio State University) Uri Shapira (Technion) Andreas Strömbergsson (Uppsala University) Jacob Tsimerman (University of Toronto) Corinna Ulcigrai (University of Bristol) Minicourse speakers include:</description></item><item><title>9 PhD Scholarships in Lisbon</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/02/9-phd-scholarships-in-lisbon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 17:07:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/02/9-phd-scholarships-in-lisbon/</guid><description>9 Doctoral Scholarships in Mathematics have been announced by the University of Lisbon under the Program LisMath 2019.
Period of the Call: from 06 March 2019 until 20 April 2019 at 14h00 (Lisbon time).
All info at: http://www.eracareers.pt/opportunities/index.aspx?task=global&amp;amp;jobId=110899</description></item><item><title>RTD di tipo A (non tenure-track), University of Pisa</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/02/temporary-research-position-in-pisa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 12:50:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/02/temporary-research-position-in-pisa/</guid><description>Bando per una posizione RTD-A (non tenure-track) nel Settore concorsuale 01/A3 (Analisi Matematica e Probabilità) presso il Dipartimento di Matematica dell&amp;rsquo;Università di Pisa, con scadenza le ore 13:00 del 18 marzo 2019.
Il bando è disponibile alla pagina:
https://alboufficiale.unipi.it/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/bandoRIC2018a1-albo.pdf</description></item><item><title>PRIN Grant Awarded!</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/02/prin-grant-awarded/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 16:34:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/02/prin-grant-awarded/</guid><description>A PRIN Grant has been awarded by the Italian Ministry of Education, University and Research to the research project &amp;ldquo;Regular and stochastic behaviour in dynamical systems&amp;rdquo;, submitted last year by several DinAmicI.
Congratulations to the PI Carlangelo Liverani and to all!
Source: https://www.miur.gov.it/documents/20182/521404/D.D.+n.+240+ALLEGATO+B+PE1.pdf/988984df-a71d-47c1-8f56-00410a65307b?version=1.0</description></item><item><title>RTD di tipo B (tenure-track), University of Pisa</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/02/rtd-di-tipo-b-tenure-track-pisa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 12:29:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/02/rtd-di-tipo-b-tenure-track-pisa/</guid><description>E` stato pubblicato sul sito web dell&amp;rsquo;Università di Pisa, il seguente bando per ricercatore a tempo determinato di tipo B (tenure-track position)
https://alboufficiale.unipi.it/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/bandoRIC2019b1-albo.pdf
per il conferimento di n. 1 posto da ricercatore a tempo determinato Settore concorsuale 01/A4
SSD: MAT/07
Scadenza: 18 marzo 2019, ore 13:00</description></item><item><title>ESA Space Debris Training Course 2019</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/02/esa-space-debris-training-course-2019/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 11:30:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/02/esa-space-debris-training-course-2019/</guid><description>ESA have opened the call for university students to participate in the space debris training course for 2019.
The course will be hosted at the ESA Academy&amp;rsquo;s Training &amp;amp; Learning Facility in ESEC-Galaxia, Transinne, Belgium, from 13 to 17 May 2019.
University students will be provided with an introduction to the concept of space debris, why it is necessary to address this problem, and how the mitigation policies set by ESA apply to missions.</description></item><item><title>Two ESR (Early Stage Researcher) positions, University of Rome Tor Vergata</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/02/two-esr-early-stage-researcher-positions-at-the-department-of-mathematics-university-of-rome-tor-vergata/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 19:14:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/02/two-esr-early-stage-researcher-positions-at-the-department-of-mathematics-university-of-rome-tor-vergata/</guid><description>As part of the Marie Curie Initial Training Network, STARDUST-R, the Department of Mathematics of the University of Rome Tor Vergata offers 2 fully funded ESR positions on the following subjects:
1) Dynamics of space debris within different orbital elements regions;
2) Proper elements for Space Debris.
More information are available at:
http://www.stardust-network.eu/about/jobs/
MSCA ELIGIBILITY CRITERION: At the time of appointment applicants should have no more than 4 years experience after graduation and should not have resided in Italy for more than 12 months in the last 3 years immediately before the appointment.</description></item><item><title>PhD position in Mathematical Neuroscience, UPC Barcelona</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/01/phd-position-on-mathematical-neuroscience-upc-barcelona/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 10:02:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/01/phd-position-on-mathematical-neuroscience-upc-barcelona/</guid><description>A PhD fellowship of the INPHINIT INCOMING programme
(BGSMATH-CRM center) is available under the supervision of G. Huguet and T. M. Seara (UPC, Barcelona). The goal is to study singular perturbation phenomena in a neuron-astrocyte model.
First deadline is February 6.
More information about the fellowship application procedure:
https://bgsmath.cat/event/inphinit-doctoral-fellowship-call-2019/
https://obrasociallacaixa.org/en/investigacion-y-becas/programa-de-becas-de-posgrado/inphinit/incoming
More information about the project:
https://bgsmath.cat/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/inphinit_2019_huguet_seara.pdf
If you know any candidate with a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in mathematics (or similar) that might be interested, please let him/her know.</description></item><item><title>RTD di tipo a, Roma La Sapienza</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/01/rtd-di-tipo-a-roma-la-sapienza/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 10:50:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/01/rtd-di-tipo-a-roma-la-sapienza/</guid><description>E` stato pubblicato sul sito web dell&amp;rsquo;Università di Roma La Sapienza, il seguente bando per ricercatore a tempo determinato di tipo A
https://web.uniroma1.it/trasparenza/sites/default/files/bando%20RTD_A%202_2019.pdf
per il conferimento di n. 1 posto da ricercatore a tempo determinato
Settore concorsuale 01/A4
SSD: MAT/07
scadenza: 7 febbraio 2019</description></item><item><title>Postdoc at Scuola Normale Superiore, Pisa</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/01/postdoc-at-scuola-normale-superiore-pisa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 21:02:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2019/01/postdoc-at-scuola-normale-superiore-pisa/</guid><description>A two-year long research position in “Dynamical Systems&amp;quot; is available at the Centro di Ricerca Matematica Ennio De Giorgi in Pisa.
PhD students can also apply, provided they obtain their PhD no later than October 1st, 2019.
The total two-year gross remuneration, inclusive of all taxes, is € 66,590.00 for each contract, corresponding to a monthly salary of approximately 2,000 Euros. An additional yearly research allowance of 1,000 Euros for exchange visits is also provided.</description></item><item><title>Postdoc positions on Dynamics of Complex Networks, UPC Barcelona</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/11/postdoc-positions-on-the-dynamic-of-complex-networks-upc-barcelona/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 16:40:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/11/postdoc-positions-on-the-dynamic-of-complex-networks-upc-barcelona/</guid><description>Dr. Romualdo Pastor-Satorras is currently offering two postdoctoral positions to work in his research group in the fields of complex systems and complex networks. The positions are located at the Department of Physics of Universitat Politecnica de Catalunya (UPC), Barcelona, Spain.
The possible topics of research for the positions are the following:
Dynamical transitions in reaction-diffusion processes on complex networks
Dynamical processes in non-Markovian temporal networks</description></item><item><title>School on Smooth Ergodic Theory and Partially Hyperbolic Systems, Loughborough, 15-18 April 2019</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/11/school-on-smooth-ergodic-theory-and-partially-hyperbolic-systems-loughborough-15-18-april-2019/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 09:28:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/11/school-on-smooth-ergodic-theory-and-partially-hyperbolic-systems-loughborough-15-18-april-2019/</guid><description>A School on Smooth Ergodic Theory and Partially Hyperbolic Systems is being organised at Loughborough, UK, from 15-18 April 2019, by Wael Bahsoun and Brian Winn.
Lecturers are J. F. Alves, S. Crovisier, I. Melbourne and tutorials are provided by M. Ruziboev. On the afternoon of 17 April, there will be a one day ergodic theory meeting; speakers are: H. Koivusalo, A. Pohl, M. Pollicott.
Financial support to cover local expenses (accommodation and meals) is available for 40 PhD students/Postdocs.</description></item><item><title>Positions as Senior Lecturer or Lecturer in Mathematics, Northumbria University</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/11/positions-as-senior-lecturer-or-lecturer-in-mathematics-northumbria-university/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 12:41:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/11/positions-as-senior-lecturer-or-lecturer-in-mathematics-northumbria-university/</guid><description>The Faculty of Engineering and Environment at Northumbria University is passionate about the principles and applications of Science and Technology in all its forms and is committed to excellence in research, teaching and innovation.
Working within the Department of Mathematics, Physics and Electrical Engineering, we seek to appoint excellent candidates who can enhance one or more of our departmental disciplines.
High-quality applications in any relevant area will be considered. In particular, the Department has distinct strength in Mathematics of Complex and Nonlinear Phenomena (MCNP) and is especially keen to hire a strong mathematician, theoretical physicist or mathematical-physicist in the areas compatible with current research directions in the MCNP group.</description></item><item><title>Seconda Giornata DinAmica: website</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/11/seconda-giornata-dinamica-website/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 20:10:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/11/seconda-giornata-dinamica-website/</guid><description>A website for the Seconda Giornata DinAmica, or 2nd DAI Day, is up and running:
https://eventi.unibo.it/dinamiciday2
The program of the day should be rather stable but we do not exclude that it might undergo small variations.
To facilitate the organization, we are asking all participants to register at the page: https://eventi.unibo.it/dinamiciday2/registrazione. Also, please download the poster and post it in your institution.
Finally, on the evening of the 21st, a number of us will meet for dinner in a restaurant to be decided.</description></item><item><title>PhD position in Mathematical Physics at the University of Groningen</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/11/phd-position-in-mathematical-physics-at-the-university-of-groningen/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 11:26:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/11/phd-position-in-mathematical-physics-at-the-university-of-groningen/</guid><description>PhD position in Mathematical Physics (218498) The research group, Dynamical Systems, Geometry and Mathematical Physics, is part of the Bernoulli Institute for Mathematics, Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence in the Faculty of Science and Engineering of the university.
The research activities of the group cover a broad and diverse spectrum of subjects in the fields of fundamental, applied and computational dynamical systems theory, classical, statistical and quantum systems and their interfaces in the light of dynamics, and theoretical and applied aspects of geometry with many connections to dynamical systems theory.</description></item><item><title>Vacancy: Researcher (type B) in Mathematical Analysis (01/A3) at SISSA, Trieste</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/11/vacancy-researcher-academic-field-01-a3-tipo-b-at-sissa-trieste/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 08:24:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/11/vacancy-researcher-academic-field-01-a3-tipo-b-at-sissa-trieste/</guid><description>Concorso for a Ricercatore a Tempo Determinato di tipo B (RTD-B) at Sissa, Trieste.
Research activity: seen the development plan of the Mathematics Area, the research activity will focus on nonlinear analysis, dynamical systems, and Hamiltonian equations.
Deadline for Applications: 22/11/2018
https://www.sissa.it/bandi/procedura-selettiva-n1-ricercatore-tempo-determinato-della-durata-di-3-anni-con-regime
http://bandi.miur.it/jobs.php/public/job/id_job/60107</description></item><item><title>Postdocs in Bologna</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/10/postdocs-in-bologna-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 21:36:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/10/postdocs-in-bologna-2/</guid><description>The Department of Mathematics of Università di Bologna has opened a call for two 1-year postdoctoral positions denominated “Starting postdoctoral position in Mathematics and Applications in Sciences, Social Sciences and Engineering”.
The positions are open to all candidates who hold a Ph.D. in Mathematics, Physics, Computer Science, Engineering, Statistics or Economics, with a preference for applicants who have obtained their Ph.D.’s in recent years. It is an “open” position in that all research areas that are currently represented in the Department will be considered (see the announcement for a list of them).</description></item><item><title>Postdoc in Porto</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/10/postdoc-in-porto-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 19:00:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/10/postdoc-in-porto-3/</guid><description>One researcher position is available within the research project “Limiting laws ruling dynamical systems”, reference PTDC/MAT-PUR/28177/2017, funded by FCT.
Applicants must hold a PhD in Mathematics or in a related field, completed at the time of application.
The research position is aimed at developing research in Mathematics within one of the following areas: Ergodic Theory or Extreme Value Theory, contributing to the research goals of the project “Limiting laws ruling dynamical systems”.</description></item><item><title>Sorrentino receives Fubini Prize!</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/10/sorrentino-receives-fubini-prize/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 21:08:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/10/sorrentino-receives-fubini-prize/</guid><description>On Thursday October 11, in a ceremony held at the Accademia delle Scienze in Turin, our own Alfonso Sorrentino received the Fubini Prize 2018. The other recipient was Giovanni Catino.
Congratulations to Alfonso from all of the DinAmicI!
 </description></item><item><title>Postdoc in Lisbon</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/10/postdoc-in-lisbon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 09:38:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/10/postdoc-in-lisbon/</guid><description>Postdoctoral fellowship in Dynamical Systems in Lisbon.
Info: http://cemapre.iseg.ulisboa.pt/lxds/opportunities/
Deadline: November 30, 2018</description></item><item><title>Seconda Giornata DinAmica, 21 December 2018</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/10/seconda-giornata-dinamica-21-december-2018/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 16:26:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/10/seconda-giornata-dinamica-21-december-2018/</guid><description>In keeping with our just-established tradition, 2018 is the year of the DinAmicI Day, the one-day long social meeting of the DinAmici. Thus, some of us (C. Bonanno, A. M. Cherubini, M. Lenci, A. Sorrentino) are organizing the
Seconda Giornata DinAmica at Accademia Nazionale dei Lincei (!) on 21 December 2018
The meeting day will include a small number of lectures/seminars and our Assemby. A detailed program will be announced soon, but for now save the date!</description></item><item><title>Workshop "Mathematical Models and Methods in Earth and Space Science", U. Rome Tor Vergata, 19-22 March 2019</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/10/workshop-mathematical-models-and-methods-in-earth-and-space-science-19-22-march-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 15:29:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/10/workshop-mathematical-models-and-methods-in-earth-and-space-science-19-22-march-2019/</guid><description>The workshop
&amp;ldquo;Mathematical Models and Methods in Earth and Space Science&amp;rdquo;
will be held at the Department of Mathematics of the University of Rome Tor Vergata from 19th to 22nd March 2019.
The workshop is one of the scientific activities which the Department organises in the next five years (2018-2022), as part of the programme &amp;ldquo;Departments of Excellence&amp;rdquo; supported by the Italian Ministry of Education, University and Research.
The following invited speakers have confirmed their participation:</description></item><item><title>Workshop "Dynamical Systems: from geometry to mechanics", U. Rome Tor Vergata, 5-8 Feb 2019</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/10/workshop-dynamical-systems-from-geometry-to-mechanics-univ-rome-tor-vergata-5-8-feb-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 15:26:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/10/workshop-dynamical-systems-from-geometry-to-mechanics-univ-rome-tor-vergata-5-8-feb-2019/</guid><description>The workshop
&amp;ldquo;Dynamical Systems: from geometry to mechanics&amp;rdquo;
will be held at the Department of Mathematics of the University of Rome Tor Vergata from 5th to 8th February 2019.
The workshop is one of the scientific activities which the Department organises in the next five years (2018-2022), as part of the programme &amp;ldquo;Departments of Excellence&amp;rdquo; supported by the Italian Ministry of Education, University and Research.
The list of invited speakers is the following:</description></item><item><title>Postdoc at Orsay</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/10/postdoc-at-orsay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 10:26:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/10/postdoc-at-orsay/</guid><description>Applications are invited for a postdoctoral position in Ergodic Theory and Dynamical Systems within the project Non Uniform Hyperbolicity in Global Dynamics of Sylvain Crovisier funded by the ERC.
Beginning: september 2019 - Length: 24 months - Location: Laboratoire de Mathématiques d’Orsay, Université Paris-Sud 11, France - Teaching: no teaching load - Income: the salary is about 2 100 euros per month Research: this postdoctoral position is funded by the ERC project Non Uniform Hyperbolicity in Global Dynamics.</description></item><item><title>Vacancy: Researcher in Mathematical Physics at University of Roma La Sapienza</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/08/vacancy-researcher-in-mathematical-physics-at-university-of-roma-la-sapienza/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 16:48:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/08/vacancy-researcher-in-mathematical-physics-at-university-of-roma-la-sapienza/</guid><description>Presso l&amp;rsquo;Università di Roma La Sapienza, è indetta la procedura per il reclutamento di un ricercatore a tempo determinato di tipo B (RTD-B) nell&amp;rsquo;ambito del settore scientifico-disciplinare di FISICA-MATEMATICA (MAT-07)
La scadenza del bando è fissato al 30 agosto 2018. Per maggiori dettagli si può consultare il bando:
https://web.uniroma1.it/trasparenza/dettaglio_bando_albo/123817
 %%%%%%%%%%% ENGLISH VERSION %%%%%%%%%%%%%%
The University of Roma La Sapienza invites applications for a 3-years position of &amp;ldquo;ricercatore a tempo determinato di tipo B [RTD-B]&amp;rdquo; (tenured position) in the scientific field of MATHEMATICAL PHYSICS.</description></item><item><title>Mather's memorial conference at Princeton University (Oct. 1-3 2018)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/07/mathers-memorial-conference-at-princeton-university-oct-1-3-2018/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 18:46:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/07/mathers-memorial-conference-at-princeton-university-oct-1-3-2018/</guid><description>Dear colleagues,
on October 1st - 3rd 2018, it will be held at Princeton University a meeting in tribute to the memory of John N. Mather (1942-2017):
http://web.math.princeton.edu/conference/mather/
Here is a list of speakers, who have accepted to give lectures on John&amp;rsquo;s fundamental contributions to many areas of mathematics:
J. Damon (Univ. North Carolina) A. Fathi (Georgia Tech) C. Fefferman (Princeton Univ.) J. Féjoz (Univ. Paris Dauphine) G. Forni (Univ. of Maryland) M.</description></item><item><title>LYSM - Call for extended missions to Italy or France</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/07/lysm-call-for-extended-missions-to-italy-or-france/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 05:08:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/07/lysm-call-for-extended-missions-to-italy-or-france/</guid><description>Dear collegues,
as many of you already know, the Hypatie Laboratory of Mathematical Sciences (LYSM) is in full activity since one year and a half, and keeps funding scientific collaborations between Italy and France, as well as conferences with an Italian-French character.
The standard activities that we fund are short missions (one or two weeks) or conferences (either participation or organization). For details, please refer to the website https://www.lysm.eu/ For funding applications, please use the web forms available on the website.</description></item><item><title>Vacancy: Researcher in Mathematical Physics at University of Roma Tre</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/07/vacancy-researcher-in-mathematical-physics-at-university-of-roma-tre/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 10:25:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/07/vacancy-researcher-in-mathematical-physics-at-university-of-roma-tre/</guid><description>Presso l&amp;rsquo;Università di Roma Tre, Dipartimento di Matematica e Fisica, è indetta la procedura per il reclutamento di un ricercatore a tempo determinato di tipo B (RTD-B) nell&amp;rsquo;ambito del settore scientifico-disciplinare di FISICA-MATEMATICA (MAT-07)
La scadenza del bando è fissato al 2 agosto 2018. Per maggiori dettagli si può consultare il bando:
https://www.albopretorionline.it/uniroma/alboente.aspx?ida=533226
 %%%%%%%%%%% ENGLISH VERSION %%%%%%%%%%%%%%
The Department of Mathematics and Physics of the University of Roma Tre invites applications for a 3-years position of &amp;ldquo;ricercatore a tempo determinato di tipo B [RTD-B]&amp;rdquo; in the scientific field of MATHEMATICAL PHYSICS.</description></item><item><title>Nominations for the Fubini Prize 2018</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/06/nominations-for-the-fubini-prize-2018/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 15:48:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/06/nominations-for-the-fubini-prize-2018/</guid><description>Nominations for the Fubini Prize 2018
We invite to nominate candidates for the Fubini Prize 2018. The prize supports a young mathematician whose researches are based in Italy (under 40 at the end of the year, and resident in Italy or temporarily resident abroad) who has obtained results in the fields of pure or applied mathematics and is recognized for his studies by the international scientific community. The age of 40 is increased by one year for each child if the mathematician is a woman.</description></item><item><title>Postdoc in Maceió</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/06/postdoc-in-maceio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 11:28:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/06/postdoc-in-maceio/</guid><description>The Graduate Program in Mathematics of the Federal University of Alagoas
PPGMAT / UFAL - informs that they are accepting applications from April 23th to June 22th of 2018 for posdoc positions at the National Postdoctoral Program (PNPD / CAPES). More information at the link below:
http://www.ufal.edu.br/unidadeacademica/im/pt-br/pos-graduacao/matematica/bolsistas/edital-02-2018 (in Portoguese)
About Maceió:
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macei%C3%B3</description></item><item><title>Call for expression of interest - Univ. Rome Tor Vergata</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/06/call-for-expression-of-interest-univ-rome-tor-vergata/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 17:23:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/06/call-for-expression-of-interest-univ-rome-tor-vergata/</guid><description>**************** CALL FOR EXPRESSION OF INTEREST *****************
The Department of Mathematics at the University of Rome Tor Vergata invites expressions of interest for Senior (Tenure-Track) Assistant Professor (&amp;lsquo;RTD-B&amp;rsquo;) and Tenured Associate Professor positions in any area of Pure and Applied Mathematics.
Who we are:
Our Department has been consistently ranked in top positions within Italy and Europe in Research Assessment Exercises held over the last decade; it is the only Italian institution ranking in the top 100 worldwide for Mathematics according to the ARWU ranking of 2017.</description></item><item><title>34 PhD fellowships at the Gran Sasso Science Institute</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/06/34-phd-fellowships-at-the-gran-sasso-science-institute/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 08:53:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/06/34-phd-fellowships-at-the-gran-sasso-science-institute/</guid><description>GSSI – Gran Sasso Science Institute advertises: 34 PhD fellowships at the GSSI: - 10 in “Astroparticle Physics” - 8 in “Mathematics in Natural, Social and Life Sciences” - 8 in “Computer Science” - 8 in “Urban Studies and Regional Science” 4 years
€ 16.159,91 gross yearly - free accommodation - free luncheon vouchers Deadline: June 20, 6 pm (CEST) Call &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; http://www.gssi.it/phd/docs/2018/CallPhDXXXIV.pdf Online Application &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; http://www.gssi.it/phd/ For more information, please consult www.</description></item><item><title>EMS Lectures Summer School, 16-18 July 2018 (University of Rome Tor Vergata)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/05/ems-lectures-summer-school-16-17-18-july-2018-department-of-mathematics-university-of-rome-tor-vergata/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 09:10:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/05/ems-lectures-summer-school-16-17-18-july-2018-department-of-mathematics-university-of-rome-tor-vergata/</guid><description>EMS LECTURES SUMMER SCHOOL - 16, 17, 18 July 2018 Department of Mathematics - University of Rome Tor VergataThe 2018 European Mathematical Society Lecturer
Prof. Gigliola Staffilani (MIT, USA)
will deliver a general Colloquium on Tuesday July 17 and a PhD course on July 17 and 18.
These lectures will be supplemented by a course of Prof. Nicola Visciglia (University of Pisa) on July 16 and 17.
Titles of the courses:Gigliola Staffilani (MIT - 2018 EMS Lecturer): On the long time dynamics for the defocusing nonlinear Schrodinger equations.</description></item><item><title>PhD of Excellence at Univ. of Rome Tor Vergata (Call 2018-2019)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/05/phd-of-excellence-at-univ-of-rome-tor-vergata-call-2018-2019/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 10:15:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/05/phd-of-excellence-at-univ-of-rome-tor-vergata-call-2018-2019/</guid><description>PhD of Excellence at Rome Tor Vergata University Call 2018-2019 Deadline June 11
The Department of Mathematics of the University of Rome Tor Vergata has been ranked first in Italy among the Departments of Mathematics in the most recent Research Assessment Exercises. The Department of Mathematics has hence benefited of an extra-funding for the period 2018-2022. These funds will be largely exploited for additional activities specifically addressed to PhD students, such as seminars, advanced courses, workshops, visiting professors; there is also specific extra-funding for students’ travels and scholarships.</description></item><item><title>Postdoc in Zurich</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/05/postdoc-in-zurich/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 09:04:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/05/postdoc-in-zurich/</guid><description>The Institute of Mathematics of the University of Zurich invites applications for
Postdoc position in Ergodic Theory and Dynamical Systems
This position will be available from August 1st, 2018 (negotiable) for 1 year. The successful candidate will be supported by Prof. Corinna Ulcigrai ERC Starting Grant ChaParDyn: Chaos in Parabolic Dynamics.
The Institute offers a stimulating research environment and excellent working conditions. The University of Zurich is an equal opportunity employer.</description></item><item><title>Associate professorship at University of Pisa</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/05/associate-professorship-at-university-of-pisa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 15:42:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/05/associate-professorship-at-university-of-pisa/</guid><description>The University of Pisa invites applications for the position of Associate Professor in Mathematical Physics (Italian SSD MAT/07). Application deadline: the application must be received by 4th June 2018 at 13:00 (Italian time). To apply: please visit the website (Italian version only)
https://www.unipi.it/ateneo/bandi/selezioni/procedure-/associati/art18c4/PA2018-4/index.htm</description></item><item><title>Postdoc in Nice</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/05/post-doc-in-nice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 11:24:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/05/post-doc-in-nice/</guid><description>Post-doc position (ANR project &amp;ldquo;DynGeo&amp;rdquo;)
The post-doc position is a pure research position without mandatory teaching (but teaching could be organised, mainly for French speakers). The post-doc will be part of the ANR grant and as such will benefit from travel money/possibility of invitations. The post-doc will also be expected to participate in the organisation of the winter school/conference in January 2019 in Nice.
Place: Nice&amp;rsquo;s University Starting Date: September 2018 Duration: 12 months Net Salary: approx.</description></item><item><title>INdAM Doctoral Programme fellowships in Mathematics</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/04/indam-doctoral-programme-fellowships-in-mathematics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 07:39:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/04/indam-doctoral-programme-fellowships-in-mathematics/</guid><description>The INdAM Doctoral Programme fellowships in Mathematics and/or Applications Cofunded by Marie Sklodowska-Curie Actions (INdAM-DP-COFUND-2015) offers PhD fellowships in the framework of the European Horizon 2020 programme “Marie Sklodowska-Curie Co-funding of Regional, National and International Programmes”. These fellowships offer to researchers from all over the world the opportunity to enter a PhD School in Italy.
On the date of the deadline for the submission of proposals, applicants must be in the first four years (full-time equivalent research experience) of their career and must not have been awarded a doctoral degree yet.</description></item><item><title>Giornata Analisi Armonica, Probabilita', e Sistemi Dinamici (16 aprile 2018)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/04/giornata-analisi-armonica-probabilita-e-sistemi-dinamici-16-aprile-2018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 18:06:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/04/giornata-analisi-armonica-probabilita-e-sistemi-dinamici-16-aprile-2018/</guid><description>Giornata di Analisi Armonica, Probabilita', e Sistemi Dinamici
Location: Aula 1E (palazzina E) Dipartimento SBAI (Universita' di Roma &amp;ldquo;La Sapienza&amp;rdquo;) via A. Scarpa 14, Roma
Lunedi' 16 aprile:
ore 14:30 Alexander BUFETOV (CNRS &amp;amp; STEKLOV INSTITUTE MOSCOW) &amp;ldquo;QUASI-SIMMETRIE DEI PROCESSI DETERMINANTALI&amp;rdquo;
ore 15:30 Yanqi QIU (CNRS &amp;amp; CHINESE ACADEMY OF SCIENCE) &amp;ldquo;DETERMINANTAL PROCESSES IN HYPERBOLIC SPACES&amp;rdquo;
ore 16:30 Pavel NIKITIN (STEKLOV INSTITUTE ST-PETERSBURG) &amp;ldquo;RIGIDITY FOR PFAFFIAN POINT PROCESSES
This project has received funding from the European Research Council (ERC) under the European Union&amp;rsquo;s Horizon 2020 research and innovation programme (grant agreement N°647133)&amp;quot;</description></item><item><title>PhD in Pisa</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/04/phd-in-pisa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 08:43:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/04/phd-in-pisa/</guid><description>In case you are looking for a PhD position in Mathematics at the University of Pisa for you or your students, I&amp;rsquo;m forwarding useful information from the PhD School Coordinator.
Dear colleagues,
in our department we are looking for students from outside Italyt hat might be interested in doing their PhD in Pisa, starting nextacademic year (that is, October/November 2018). I ask your help to bring this message to the attention of students in your department that might be interested.</description></item><item><title>Summer School in Dynamics at ICTP, 16-27 July 2018</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/03/summer-school-in-dynamics-at-ictp-16-27-july-2018/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 03:52:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/03/summer-school-in-dynamics-at-ictp-16-27-july-2018/</guid><description>A Summer School in Dynamical Systems which will be held at ICTP, Trieste (Italy) on 16-27 July 2018.
http://indico.ictp.it/event/8325/
The school is targeted to Masters and beginning PhD students and aims at introducing a variety of fundamental ideas and techniques in dynamics. The first week will not assume prior knowledge in the field of dynamical systems. Students can also register for the second week only.
Female students are especially encouraged to apply.</description></item><item><title>3 post-doc positions at University of Padova</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/03/3-post-doc-positions-at-university-of-padova/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 17:00:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/03/3-post-doc-positions-at-university-of-padova/</guid><description>Announcement for 3 post-doc positions at University of Padova, under the supervision of Gabriella Pinzari.
The deadline to apply is April 3, 2018. Salary amount about 27,000 euros.
Expected start date: May 2nd.
http://www.math.unipd.it/it/news/?id=2217
http://www.math.unipd.it/it/news/?id=2218</description></item><item><title>Postdoctoral position in São Carlos, Brazil</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/03/postdoctoral-position-in-sao-carlos-brazil/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 18:44:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/03/postdoctoral-position-in-sao-carlos-brazil/</guid><description>The University of São Paulo campus São Carlos invites potential candidates for a two-year Postdoctoral position, renewable up to four years. Looking for candidates whose research is related to the interests of the Dynamical Systems group (see http://sisdin.icmc.usp.br): Equilibrium states for partially hyperbolic diffeomorphisms (in particular measures of maximal entropy), Stable ergodicity for conservative diffeomorphisms, Comparing classical partially hyperbolic dynamical systems and random walks, Equilibrium states for action of groups, Piecewise expanding transformations with low regularity, Renormalization Theory and universality in one-dimensional dynamics Deformation theory in one- dimensional dynamics Dynamics defined by action of groups: Anosov (sub)systems and their representations in SL(n,R).</description></item><item><title>Vacancy: Tenure-track Researcher in Mathematical Physics (U. Rome Tor Vergata)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/02/vacancy-tenure-track-researcher-in-mathematical-physics-u-rome-tor-vergata/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 15:13:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/02/vacancy-tenure-track-researcher-in-mathematical-physics-u-rome-tor-vergata/</guid><description>Presso l&amp;rsquo;Università degli studi di Roma &amp;ldquo;Tor Vergata&amp;rdquo;, Dipartimento di Matematica, è indetta la procedura per il reclutamento di un ricercatore a tempo determinato di tipo B (RTD-B) nell&amp;rsquo;ambito del settore scientifico-disciplinare di FISICA-MATEMATICA (MAT-07)
Le domande devono essere presentate entro la data del 15/03/2018 Il bando e il fac-simile della domanda sono accessibili alla pagina web http://web.uniroma2.it/module/name/Content/newlang/italiano/action/showpage/navpath/CON/content_id/51738/section_id/6206
Il Dipartimento di Matematica - Univ. Roma Tor Vergata e' Dipartimento di Eccellenza 2018-2022.</description></item><item><title>School "Stable and Chaotic Motions in the Planetary Problem"</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/02/school-stable-and-chaotic-motions-in-the-planetary-problem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 16:18:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/02/school-stable-and-chaotic-motions-in-the-planetary-problem/</guid><description>The school:
&amp;ldquo;Stable and Chaotic Motions in the Planetary Problem&amp;rdquo;
will take place in Asiago (Italy), June 10-15 2018, funded by the homonym ERC project Stable and Chaotic Motions in the Planetary problem.
The aim of this school is to study in depth the dynamics of planetary systems from the underlying mathematical theories coming from perturbation theories and going back to A. N. Kolmogorov, V. I. Arnold and J. Moser, up to the recent astronomical observations of comets, asteroids and exoplanets from ground and space.</description></item><item><title>Perspectives in Hamiltonian Dynamics (Venice, June 18-22)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/02/perspectives-in-hamiltonian-dynamics-venice-june-18-22/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 16:16:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/02/perspectives-in-hamiltonian-dynamics-venice-june-18-22/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Perspectives in Hamiltonian dynamics&amp;rdquo;
will be held in Venice (Italy) June 18-22 2018, funded by the homonym ERC project Stable and Chaotic Motions in the Planetary problem.
The aim of this conference is to gather specialists working in the fields of Hamiltonian systems, with a focus on near integrable systems, celestial mechanics, perturbative techniques, Kolmogorov-Arnold-Moser and Nekhorossev theories, Arnold instability.
The following speakers confirmed their participation:
Massimiliano Berti (Scuola Italiana di Studi Superiori Avanzati, Trieste) Alessandra Celletti (Universita` Tor Vergata, Roma) Alain Chenciner (Institut de mécanique céleste et de calcul des Ephemerides, Paris) Amadeu Delshams (Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya, Barcelona) Holger Dullin (University of Sydney) Christos Effthimiopoulos (Academy of Athens) Bassam Fayad (Institut de Mathématiques de Jussieu, Paris) Marian Gidea (Yeshiva University, New York) Giovanni Gronchi (Universita` di Pisa) Marcel Guardia (Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya, Barcelona) Vadim Kaloshin (University of Maryland) Sergei Kuksin (Universit?</description></item><item><title>Position as Associate Professor/Professor in Mathematics at Northumbria University, UK</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/01/position-as-associate-professor-professor-in-mathematics-at-northumbria-university-uk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 08:37:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/01/position-as-associate-professor-professor-in-mathematics-at-northumbria-university-uk/</guid><description>A position as Associate Professor/Professor in Mathematics has been opened at Northumbria University.
https://work4.northumbria.ac.uk/work-for-us/details/?roleId=461
Excellent candidates in the mathematics of complex and nonlinear phenomena (https://www.northumbria.ac.uk/mcnp) are particularly encouraged to apply, though high-quality applications in any area of Mathematics will be considered. The vacancy will close on the 28th of February 2018.</description></item><item><title>London Mathematical Laboratory Summer School 2018</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/01/london-mathematical-laboratory-summer-school-2018/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 15:26:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/01/london-mathematical-laboratory-summer-school-2018/</guid><description>Applications are invited for the London Mathematical Laboratory (LML) Summer School from Monday 23rd July – Friday 17th August 2018. Successful applicants will carry out a four-week research project under supervision at LML. Travel to and from London, accommodation, and a stipend of £1,000 will be provided.
Applicants should hold or be studying for a degree in a relevant subject. The projects are envisaged as suitable for late-stage undergraduates or early-stage postgraduates.</description></item><item><title>Associate professorship at Scuola Normale Superiore in Pisa</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/01/associate-professorship-at-scuola-normale-superiore-in-pisa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 10:37:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2018/01/associate-professorship-at-scuola-normale-superiore-in-pisa/</guid><description>The Classe di Scienze of the Scuola Normale Superiore in Pisa invites applications for the position of Associate Professor,
specialty Mathematical Physics (Italian SSD MAT/07). The ideal candidate research interest should focus on dynamical systems (classical or quantum) and ergodic theory.
Application deadline: the application must be received by 8th February, 2018 at 11:59 p.m. C.E.T. at the Scuola Normale Superiore
To apply: please visit the website
https://en.sns.it/bando/associate-professor-academic-discipline-mathematical-physics</description></item><item><title>Ph.D. Studentships at Loughborough</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/12/ph-d-studentships-at-loughborough/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 18:03:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/12/ph-d-studentships-at-loughborough/</guid><description>Ph.D. Studentships at Loughborough University
**Title: **Rare Events in Dynamical Systems via Transfer Operator Techniques
Supervisor: Wael Bahsoun (W.Bahsoun@lboro.ac.uk; phone +44-15-09-222883).
Nature of work: Theory
Area: Mathematics: Ergodic Theory and Dynamical Systems
Brief description: The study of rare events in dynamical systems is currently one of the most active branches of research in ergodic theory. In part, this is due to their interesting applications in earth and ocean sciences. An example of a rare event in dynamical systems appears in the study of ‘open’ systems where orbits infrequently escape from the domain, typically by falling into a small “hole” in the phase space.</description></item><item><title>8 Postdocs (including Dynamics) in São Paulo</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/12/8-postdocs-including-dynamics-in-sao-paulo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 18:00:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/12/8-postdocs-including-dynamics-in-sao-paulo/</guid><description>Postdoctoral positions at the University of São Paulo, Brazil
The Low Dimensional Dynamics and Geometry Group of the Institute of Mathematics and Statistics of the University of São Paulo (IME-USP), invites applications for 8 postdoctoral positions.
The positions are for two years, renewable twice for up to four years. There are no teaching responsibilities. We are looking for candidates with strong research potential in areas of interest to the group: real and complex dynamics in low dimensions, topological dynamics on surfaces, low dimensional geometry and topology, hyperbolic geometry of 3-manifolds, Teichmüller theory, symplectic geometry and topology, ergodic theory are among the groups interests.</description></item><item><title>Postdoctoral position at Monash University, Melbourne</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/12/postdoctoral-position-at-monash-university-melbourne/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 18:31:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/12/postdoctoral-position-at-monash-university-melbourne/</guid><description>A candidate is sought for a position for the role of Postdoctoral Research Fellow on a project studying chaotic dynamical systems on 3-dimensional manifolds. Candidates with expertise in any of the fields of dynamical systems, ergodic theory, foliation theory, and the geometry and topology of 3-manifolds are strongly encouraged to apply.
The Postdoctoral Fellow will conduct research at the School of Mathematical Sciences, Monash University, under the guidance of Dr Andy Hammerlindl.</description></item><item><title>Postdoctoral position at UNSW, Sydney</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/12/postdoctoral-position-at-unsw-sydney/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 18:20:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/12/postdoctoral-position-at-unsw-sydney/</guid><description>Applications are sought for a Postdoctoral Research Fellow position in Smooth Ergodic Theory and Dynamical Systems in UNSW’s School of Mathematics and Statistics. Although experience in both Smooth Ergodic Theory and Dynamical Systems is preferred, all candidates with strong qualifications in Dynamical Systems and related fields of research are encouraged to apply and will be carefully considered.
About the role
• $89,051 - $96,677 plus 17% superannuation
• Full-time position for a fixed term of up to 2 years with the possibility of extension of up to a further year.</description></item><item><title>Postdocs in all areas of mathematics at ICTP Trieste</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/12/postdocs-in-all-areas-of-mathematics-at-ictp-trieste/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 10:13:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/12/postdocs-in-all-areas-of-mathematics-at-ictp-trieste/</guid><description>Every year, ICTP&amp;rsquo;s Mathematics section offers research opportunities for outstanding mathematicians from developing countries, including postdoctorates. The section is now accepting applications for its Postdoctoral Fellowships; the deadline is 7 January 2018.
Postdoctoral Fellowships are intended for young mathematicians with a strong research record. Fellows must have completed a PhD in mathematics prior to the start of their fellowship. Women are particularly encouraged to apply. The fellowships have a 12-month duration with a possible extension for a further 12 months; the initial period will be 1 September 2018 - 31 August 2019.</description></item><item><title>Postdocs in Bologna</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/11/postdocs-in-bologna/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 22:15:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/11/postdocs-in-bologna/</guid><description>The Department of Mathematics of Università di Bologna has opened a call for two 1-year postdoctoral positions denominated &amp;ldquo;Starting postdoctoral position in Mathematics and Applications in Sciences, Social Sciences and Engineering&amp;rdquo;.
The positions are open to all candidates who hold a Ph.D. in Mathematics, Physics, Computer Science, Engineering, Statistics or Economics, with a preference for applicants who have obtained their Ph.D.&amp;rsquo;s in recent years. It is an &amp;ldquo;open&amp;rdquo; position in that all research areas that are currently represented in the Department will be considered (see the announcement for a list of them).</description></item><item><title>Ph.D. positions in Cardiff (UK)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/11/ph-d-positions-in-cardiff-uk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 07:16:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/11/ph-d-positions-in-cardiff-uk/</guid><description>Dr Jonathan Ben-Artzi is advertising PhD studentships in Cardiff that are fully funded for 3.5 years for EU nationals.
Dr Ben-Artzi is keen to advise on problems in kinetic theory and dynamical systems, in particular long time behaviour.
Anyone interested should contact ben-artzij@cardiff.ac.uk.
The deadline is in January.</description></item><item><title>Postdoc in Oxford</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/11/postdoc-in-oxford/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 09:11:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/11/postdoc-in-oxford/</guid><description>The Hooke and Titchmarsh fellowships have now been advertised:
https://www.maths.ox.ac.uk/node/26956 (Hooke - up to 3 positions, in applied mathematics)https://www.maths.ox.ac.uk/node/26957 (Titchmarsh
up to 4 positions, in pure mathematics) These are 3-year independent fellowships, research focussed with some light teaching.
Deadline is 8th December.</description></item><item><title>Assistant Professorship (non-tenure track) at the University of Pisa</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/11/assistant-professorship-non-tenure-track-at-the-university-of-pisa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 18:16:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/11/assistant-professorship-non-tenure-track-at-the-university-of-pisa/</guid><description>Applications are warmly invited for 1 position as &amp;ldquo;Junior assistant professor&amp;rdquo; (Ricercatore a Tempo Determinato di tipo A) in &amp;ldquo;Mathematical Physics&amp;rdquo; at the University of Pisa. The duration is 3 years.
The position carries a teaching load in Italian of up to 60 hours per year.
Deadline: applications should arrive before 4th December.
The instructions to apply may be found in the announcement (selection code A_15): https://alboufficiale.unipi.it/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Bando_a_19_posti-2017_albo.pdf
For further information, please contact claudio.</description></item><item><title>Workshop "From order to chaos", Pisa, 9-14 April 2018</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/11/workshop-from-order-to-chaos-pisa-9-14-april-2018/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 17:56:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/11/workshop-from-order-to-chaos-pisa-9-14-april-2018/</guid><description>All info at: http://www.crm.sns.it/event/419/</description></item><item><title>2 Assistant Professorships (non tenure-track) at the University of Padova</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/10/2-assistant-professorships-non-tenure-track-ricercatore-a-tempo-determinato-lett-a-l-2402010-at-the-university-of-padova/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 07:39:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/10/2-assistant-professorships-non-tenure-track-ricercatore-a-tempo-determinato-lett-a-l-2402010-at-the-university-of-padova/</guid><description>2 job vacancies at the Department of Mathematics &amp;ldquo;Tullio levi-Civita&amp;rdquo; at the University of Padova
The offered positions are 2 Assistant Professorships (non tenure-track)
&amp;ldquo;Ricercatore a Tempo determinato lett. a) L. 240/2010&amp;rdquo;- . The time commitment is for 3 years.
The positions are funded by the ERC project &amp;ldquo;Stable and Chaotic Motions in the Planetary Problem&amp;rdquo;. The project is around KAM, Nekhorossev and instabilities theories in planetary systems. The winner candidate will be part of the team of the project and will work around its themes.</description></item><item><title>Postdoc in Marseille</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/10/postdoc-in-marseille/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 13:53:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/10/postdoc-in-marseille/</guid><description>Institut de Mathematiques de Marseille announces CNRS ERC Post-Doctoral Research Positions in Mathematics.
The positions are within the project &amp;ldquo;Intermediate Chaos&amp;rdquo; funded by the European Research Council, PI: Alexander Bufetov.
The project is devoted to ergodic theory and probability, with an emphasis on point processes.
Applicants should have a PhD degree at the time of starting the job. Applicants are advised to include the following: - cover letter / statement of purpose; - research statement; - CV and list of publications.</description></item><item><title>SNS Pisa - Research contracts “Junior Visiting Positions” in mathematics</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/10/sns-pisa-research-contracts-junior-visiting-positions-in-mathematics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 15:14:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/10/sns-pisa-research-contracts-junior-visiting-positions-in-mathematics/</guid><description>Position n. 4: Dynamical Systems, as part of the research project “Dynamics and Information Theory Research Institute” (Convenzione 2014 Scuola-Unicredit S.p.a.).
https://en.sns.it/bando/research-contracts-named-%E2%80%9Cjunior-visiting-positions%E2%80%9D-field-mathematics-0</description></item><item><title>Scholarships for mathematicians granted by Accademia dei Lincei</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/10/scholarships-for-mathematicians-granted-by-accademia-dei-lincei/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 12:54:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/10/scholarships-for-mathematicians-granted-by-accademia-dei-lincei/</guid><description>Announcements (in Italian) on the Accademia dei Lincei website:
«Mino Bontempelli» 6-month post-Master&amp;rsquo;s scholarship in the Mathematical Sciences (deadline: 30 November 2017) 4 Royal Society scholarships for 5-month research visits to Great Britain (deadline: 30 November 2017)  </description></item><item><title>Postdoc in Grenoble</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/10/postdoc-in-grenoble/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 12:36:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/10/postdoc-in-grenoble/</guid><description>Postdoctoral research position available:
Beginning: October 2018 (exact date open to discussion)
Length: 24 months
Location: Based in Grenoble (France) at Fourier Institute. During the second year, possibility of long visits to other places of the ANR project, especially the University Paris-Sud.
Research: This postdoctoral position is funded by the ANR project ISDEEC. This project concerns the qualitative dynamics of PDEs and ODEs and lies in the interface of dynamical systems theory, PDE techniques, control theory, geometry, functional analysis&amp;hellip; One of the main topics of the doctoral thesis (PhD) of the candidate should concern either dynamical systems or PDE’s or control theory.</description></item><item><title>Postdoc in Orsay</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/10/postdoc-in-orsay/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 12:30:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/10/postdoc-in-orsay/</guid><description>Applications are invited for a postdoctoral position in Ergodic Theory and Dynamical Systems within the project Non Uniform Hyperbolicity in Global Dynamics of Sylvain Crovisier funded by the ERC.
Beginning: September 2018
Length: 24 months
Location: Laboratoire de Mathématiques d’Orsay, Université Paris-Sud, France
Research: This postdoctoral position is funded by the ERC project Non Uniform Hyperbolicity in Global Dynamics. This project studies the qualitative, symbolic and probabilistic aspects of the dynamics of differentiable dynamical systems (diffeomorphisms or flows).</description></item><item><title>Postdoc position in Roma "Tor Vergata"</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/10/postdoc-position-in-roma-tor-vergata/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 19:12:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/10/postdoc-position-in-roma-tor-vergata/</guid><description>A 1-year postdoc position is available in Rome Tor Vergata within the SIR project “New methods in holomorphic iteration”. There is no teaching load. The research theme is several complex variables and holomorphic dynamics. Deadline for application is November 1st.
The chosen candidates will work in Rome, starting January/February 2018. Information and instructions to apply can be found at
http://web.uniroma2.it/module/name/Content/newlang/italiano/action/showpage/navpath/RIC/content_id/46403/section_id/4992
For more information, please write to arosio@mat.uniroma2.it.</description></item><item><title>Postdoc in Padova</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/09/postdoc-in-padova/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 11:07:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/09/postdoc-in-padova/</guid><description>One-year postdoctoral position at the Department of Mathematics of the University of Padova.
Project: &amp;ldquo;Stable and Chaotic Motions in the Planetary Problem&amp;rdquo;
Supervisor: Gabriella Pinzari
Deadline: 5 October 2017
Info (in Italian): http://www.math.unipd.it/it/news/?id=2076</description></item><item><title>Conference "Analysis and Dynamics": in honour of Luigi Chierchia's 60th Birthday</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/09/conference-analysis-and-dynamics-in-honour-of-luigi-chierchias-60th-birthday/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 08:18:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/09/conference-analysis-and-dynamics-in-honour-of-luigi-chierchias-60th-birthday/</guid><description>Analysis and Dynamics  Conference in occasion of Luigi Chierchia's 60th BirthdayMarina di San Gregorio, Lecce 12-15 October 2017 http://ricerca.mat.uniroma3.it/users/procesi/ConvegnoLuigi60.html  Invited speakers:G. Benettin (Universita di Padova) W. Craig (Mc Master University) A. Delshams (​Universitat Politecnica de Catalunya) A. Fathi (GeorgiaTech University) J. Fejoz (UniversiteParis Dauphine &amp;amp; Observatoire de Paris) V. Gelfreich (Warwick University) M. Guzzo (Universita di Padova) H. Ito (Kanazawa University) V. Kaloshin (University of Maryland) T. Kappeler (Universitat Zurich) S.</description></item><item><title>Winter school "Recent advances in Hamiltonian dynamics and symplectic topology", Padova, February 2018</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/08/winter-school-recent-advances-in-hamiltonian-dynamics-and-symplectic-topology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 16:00:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/08/winter-school-recent-advances-in-hamiltonian-dynamics-and-symplectic-topology/</guid><description>Winter school *&amp;ldquo;Recent advances in Hamiltonian dynamics and symplectic topology”, * February 12 to 16, 2018, University of Padova. For more information see:
https://events.math.unipd.it/hamschool2018
The school will cover lodging expenses of a limited number of participants. Interested people are invited to send an e-mail to this address:
hamschool2018@gmail.com
Organizing committee:
O. Bernardi, F. Cardin, G. Pinzari, L. Zanelli (University of Padova) A. Sorrentino (University of Rome &amp;ldquo;Tor Vergata”) A. Florio (Université d&amp;rsquo;Avignon)</description></item><item><title>Workshop "Dynamical Systems and Perturbations", Saint Petersburg, October 2017</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/08/workshop-dynamical-systems-and-perturbations-saint-petersburg-october-2017/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 17:24:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/08/workshop-dynamical-systems-and-perturbations-saint-petersburg-october-2017/</guid><description>The workshop &amp;ldquo;Dynamical Systems and Perturbations&amp;rdquo;, in occasion with Sergei Pilyugin 70th birthday, will take place at the Euler International Mathematical Institute, Saint-Petersburg, on 2-4 October 2017.
The following sessions are planned: - shadowing theory of approximate trajectories - hyperbolicity and structural stability - spaces of dynamical systems and generic dynamics - evolutionary equations - group actions - parameter identifiable systems - free topics.
Limited financial support is available on request.</description></item><item><title>Postdoc at Exeter</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/08/postdoc-at-exeter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 13:41:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/08/postdoc-at-exeter/</guid><description>Postdoctoral position in Dynamical Systems at the University of Exeter
This post is available from 01 November 2017 for 36 months to support the work of Mark Holland.
The University of Exeter is a Russell Group university that combines world-class research with very high levels of student satisfaction. Exeter has over 21,000 students from more than 130 different countries and is in the top 1% of universities in the world with 98% of its research rated as being of international quality.</description></item><item><title>Postdoc in Porto</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/08/postdoc-in-porto-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 13:39:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/08/postdoc-in-porto-2/</guid><description>Applications are invited for a postdoctoral position (BPD) in Ergodic Theory and Dynamical Systems within the project PTDC/MAT-CAL/3884/2014 funded by the FCT (Portuguese Science and Technology Foundation).
Applicants must hold a PhD in Mathematics or in a related field, preferably obtained less than 6 years ago and have research experience in at least one of the main research areas of the project.
The initial contract will be for 12 months, possibly extended to 15 months.</description></item><item><title>Nostrification of Ph.D. qualifications awarded by foreign universities</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/08/nostrification-of-ph-d-qualifications-awarded-by-foreign-universities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 17:23:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/08/nostrification-of-ph-d-qualifications-awarded-by-foreign-universities/</guid><description>This year there have been some upgrades to the Italian laws ruling the recruitment in the universities. One of these upgrades concerns the documents required to apply for calls for the positions of &amp;ldquo;junior or senior RTD&amp;rdquo; (temporary assistant professor).
The main change is about the document proving the Ph.D. qualification. In particular, some universities (please don&amp;rsquo;t ask why not all of them) are now asking that participants to a call declare that they have obtained the nostrification of the Ph.</description></item><item><title>PhD Scholarship on "Topological characterization of network dynamics", Florence</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/07/phd-scholarship-on-topological-characterization-of-network-dynamics-florence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 19:24:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/07/phd-scholarship-on-topological-characterization-of-network-dynamics-florence/</guid><description>The Ph.D. school in Information Engineering of the University of Florence has recently funded a scholarship in &amp;ldquo;Topological characterization of network dynamics&amp;rdquo;. The scholarship falls within the university program in multidisciplinary education, and therefore it is open to graduate students coming from various fields, such as Engineering, Physics and Mathematics. The scholarship lasts 3 years, and it is completely funded during this time. The winner has to attend the Ph.D. school during these years and will have to write a dissertation to earn the PhD degree.</description></item><item><title>Conference on Hamiltonian Systems, in tribute to the memory of John Mather (1942-2017).</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/06/conference-on-hamiltonian-systems-in-tribute-to-the-memory-of-john-mather-1942-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 08:28:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/06/conference-on-hamiltonian-systems-in-tribute-to-the-memory-of-john-mather-1942-2017/</guid><description>Conference on Hamiltonian Systems, in tribute to the memory of John Mather (1942-2017).
The meeting will take place from 30th october to 3rd november 2017 in Ascona (Switzerland) and it will be generously supported by ETH-ITS Zurich and by “Centro Congressi Stefano Franscini” in Ascona.
The list of invited speakers and other relevant information can be retrieved from the following website: http://www.eth-its.ethz.ch/hamiltonian-systems-csf.html
We will be able to cover lodging/boarding expenses (from sunday evening to friday afternoon) to a number of participants, in the limit of the maximal occupancy of the conference centre.</description></item><item><title>School "Stable and Chaotic Motions in the Planetary Problem", Asiago, June 10-15, 2018</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/06/school-stable-and-chaotic-motions-in-the-planetary-problem-osservatorio-di-asiago-june-10-15-2018/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 08:35:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/06/school-stable-and-chaotic-motions-in-the-planetary-problem-osservatorio-di-asiago-june-10-15-2018/</guid><description>https://677793stablechaoticplanetm.wordpress.com/dissemination-activities/</description></item><item><title>INdAM Travel Grants</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/05/indam-travel-grants/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 13:29:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/05/indam-travel-grants/</guid><description>3- to 6-Month Travel Grants financed by INdAM.
Deadline: June 15, 2017
Announcement and application form (in Italian): http://www.altamatematica.it/it/node/551
 </description></item><item><title>Postdoc in Pisa</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/05/postdoc-in-pisa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 10:27:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/05/postdoc-in-pisa/</guid><description>Applications are invited for a postdoctoral position in &amp;ldquo;Ergodic properties of dynamical systems&amp;rdquo; within the research project PRA_2017_22 funded by the University of Pisa.
For all information see
https://www.unipi.it/ateneo/bandi/assegni/pra2017/matemati/index.htm</description></item><item><title>INdAM Research Projects for Young Researchers</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/04/indam-research-projects-for-young-researchers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 17:08:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/04/indam-research-projects-for-young-researchers/</guid><description>The Italian National Institute for Advanced Mathematics (INdAM) calls for 6 Research Projects to be submitted by &amp;ldquo;Young Researchers&amp;rdquo;.
The goal of the initiative is to foster the rise of new leaders in mathematical research, who will be able to compete for ERC Starting Grants and similar Research Funding Schemes.
The selected projects will have the duration of 1 year with no possibility of renewal and will be given funds for a postdoctoral position, which might be filled by the applicant him/herself.</description></item><item><title>DinAmicI V - website and poster</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/03/dinamici-v-website-and-poster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 16:27:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/03/dinamici-v-website-and-poster/</guid><description>A website for our upcoming INdAM Workshop
DinAmicI V Modern Trends in the Ergodic Theory of Dynamical Systems
is up and running: http://dinamici5.dm.unibo.it/
We encourage you to visit the site, download the workshop&amp;rsquo;s wonderful poster and post it somewhere in your institution. (Warning: the poster might be updated before the start of the workshop.)</description></item><item><title>PhD positions at GSSI</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/03/phd-positions-at-gssi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 21:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/03/phd-positions-at-gssi/</guid><description>The Gran Sasso Science Institute (GSSI) has opened a new call for PhD applications (deadline 31 May 2017).
40 positions (all with fellowship) are available starting from 1 November 2017 in:
Astroparticle Physics Mathematics in Natural, Social and Life Sciences Computer Science Urban Studies and Regional Science GSSI is an international PhD school and a center for advanced studies established in L&amp;rsquo;Aquila (Italy). Its purpose is to form high level human capital, integrating education and research in a lively interdisciplinary environment.</description></item><item><title>Postdoc in Salvador, Bahia, Brazil</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/03/postdoc-in-salvador-bahia-brazil/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 23:19:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/03/postdoc-in-salvador-bahia-brazil/</guid><description>https://pgmat.ufba.br/pt-br/aberta-selecao-de-bolsista-de-pos-doutorado-pnpd-ufba
A vacancy for a post-doctorate research scholarship in the framework of &amp;ldquo;Programa Nacional de Pós Doutorado PNPD-CAPES&amp;rdquo; (National post-doctoral programme PNPD-CAPES) associated to the PhD Program in Mathematics UFBA/UFAL is available from May 1st, 2017.
The applicant is expected to be a Doctorate with high research potential in Mathematics, without a job contract, and with potential for interaction with the research groups of the PhD Program. The value of the scholarship is R$4100,00 (four thousand and one houndred brazillian real) per month.</description></item><item><title>Postdoc in Porto</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/03/postdoc-in-porto/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 23:22:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/03/postdoc-in-porto/</guid><description>Applications are invited for a postdoctoral position (BPD) in Ergodic Theory and Dynamical Systems within the project PTDC/MAT-CAL/3884/2014 funded by the FCT (Portuguese Science and Technology Foundation).
Applicants must hold a PhD in Mathematics or in a related field, preferably obtained less than 6 years ago and have research experience in at least one of the main research areas of the project.
The initial contract will be for 12 months, renewable for another 12 months on mutual agreement.</description></item><item><title>Spring Doctoral School in Lecce, Italy</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/02/spring-doctoral-school-in-lecce-italy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 13:11:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/02/spring-doctoral-school-in-lecce-italy/</guid><description>The 2017 CRITICS Spring Doctoral School will be held at University of Salento in Lecce from April 18th to 22nd:
http://www.criticsitn.eu/wp/?page_id=468
The school is one of the activities of the ITN CRITICS:
http://wwwf.imperial.ac.uk/~mrasmuss/critics/index.php
and everybody interested, in particular graduate students, is very welcome to participate.</description></item><item><title>Dynamics in Italy - June 2017</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/02/dynamics-in-italy-june-2017/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 10:49:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/02/dynamics-in-italy-june-2017/</guid><description>Italy is the place to be for young and old dynamicists this coming June 2017. Three amazing events one after the other in Rome, Pisa and Trieste.
5-9 June, Fifth Workshop of the DinAmicI, Rome http://dinamici5.dm.unibo.it/
12-16 June, School on Hyperbolic Dynamics, Pisa http://crm.sns.it/event/410/
19-23 June, Workshop on Hyperbolic Dynamics, Trieste http://indico.ictp.it/event/7970/
Further details below and on the websites. Please distribute this to anyone interested.
****************************************************
The Fifth Workshop of the DinAmicI (https://www.</description></item><item><title>Houston Summer School on Dynamical Systems - May 2017</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/02/houston-summer-school-on-dynamical-systems-may-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 15:31:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/02/houston-summer-school-on-dynamical-systems-may-2017/</guid><description>The Department of Mathematics at University of Houston will host the fifth annual Houston Summer School on Dynamical Systems from May 17-25, 2017.
As in past years, the school is designed for graduate students; however, this year there will also be an opportunity for undergraduate students to participate, arriving two days early and then staying for the main event.
The following short courses are planned:
Statistical properties in hyperbolic dynamics (Vaughn Climenhaga, Will Ott, Andrew Török - University of Houston) Partially hyperbolic dynamics (Todd Fisher - Brigham Young University) Dynamical methods in Diophantine approximation (Alan Haynes - University of Houston) Dynamics of group actions on homogeneous spaces (Anish Ghosh - Tata Institute of Fundamental Research) Linearly recurrent systems (Valérie Berthé - Univ.</description></item><item><title>Postdoctoral positions at ICMAT - Madrid</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/02/postdoctoral-positions-at-icmat-madrid/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 15:26:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/02/postdoctoral-positions-at-icmat-madrid/</guid><description>The Instituto de Ciencias Matemáticas (ICMAT-Institute of Mathematical Sciences) offers postdoctoral appointments for researchers in Mathematics with an excellent curriculum who wish to pursue their research career at the ICMAT.
Deadline March 1, 2017
For further information visit https://www.icmat.es/severo-ochoa/HumanResources/ICMat_Postdoc2017</description></item><item><title>Ergodic Theory, Algorithms and Rigorous Computations, Warwick, 3-7 April 2017</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/02/ergodic-theory-algorithms-and-rigorous-computations-warwick-3-7-april-2017/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 08:24:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2017/02/ergodic-theory-algorithms-and-rigorous-computations-warwick-3-7-april-2017/</guid><description>Workshop &amp;ldquo;Ergodic Theory, Algorithms and Rigorous Computations&amp;rdquo;
Warwick, 3-7 April 2017
Organising Committee: W.Bahsoun (Loughborough), S.Galatolo (Pisa), M.Pollicott (Warwick), B.Saussol (Brest) and S.Vaienti (Toulon)
Local Organisers: W.Bahsoun and M.Pollicott
Confirmed Speakers: Viviane Baladi (MJ-PRG, CNRS) Michael Dellnitz (Paderbon) Mark Demers (Fairfield) Frédéric Faure (Grenoble) Gary Froyland (New South Wales) Georg Gottwald (Sydney) Sébastien Gouëzel (Rennes) Oliver Jenkinson (QM-UL) Oliver Junge (Munich) Kathrin Padberg-Gehle (Dresden) Carlangelo Liverani (Rome II) Ian Melbourne (Warwick) Francoise Pene (Brest) Cecilia González-Tokman (Queensland) Warwick Tucker (Uppsala) Polina Vytnova (QM-UL)</description></item><item><title>One-day workshop on Dynamical Systems in Trieste | 11.01.17</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/12/one-day-workshop-on-dynamical-systems-in-trieste-11-01-17/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 11:22:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/12/one-day-workshop-on-dynamical-systems-in-trieste-11-01-17/</guid><description>One-day workshop on Dynamical Systems in Trieste, Wednesday 11 January 2017.
Talks:
Stefano Galatolo (Pisa), &amp;ldquo;A functional analytic approach for skew products with weakly contracting fibers. Application to the statistical stability.&amp;rdquo; Maurizio Monge (UFRJ, Brazil), &amp;ldquo;Rigorous computation in random dynamics and computer-aided proof of noise-induced-order.&amp;rdquo; Davide Ravotti (Bristol), &amp;ldquo;Ergodic properties of area-preserving flows on compact surfaces.&amp;rdquo; Oliver Butterley (ICTP), &amp;ldquo;Open Sets of Exponentially Mixing Anosov Flows.&amp;rdquo; Further information: http://indico.</description></item><item><title>Spring school in convex symplectic geometry: Bochum, 20-24 February 2017</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/12/convex-symplectic-geometry-school-20-24-feb-2017-bochum-germany/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 17:46:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/12/convex-symplectic-geometry-school-20-24-feb-2017-bochum-germany/</guid><description>Spring school in convex symplectic geometry: Bochum, 20-24 February 2017
For more information see:
http://www.ruhr-uni-bochum.de/ffm/Lehrstuehle/Lehrstuhl-VII/springschool17.html.en
Note: The school will cover travel and lodging expenses of a limited number of participants. See the above web site for instructions about how to participate.
 </description></item><item><title>1 Postdoctoral position in Applied Mathematics / Mathematical Physics at Politecnico di Torino</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/12/1-postdoctoral-position-in-applied-mathematics-mathematical-physics-department-at-politecnico-di-torino/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 14:12:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/12/1-postdoctoral-position-in-applied-mathematics-mathematical-physics-department-at-politecnico-di-torino/</guid><description>1 Postdoctoral position (type B) in Applied Mathematics / Mathematical Physics, Department of Mathematical Sciences &amp;ldquo;G. L. Lagrange&amp;rdquo;, Politecnico di Torino
Deadline for applications: 12th January 2017
Call: http://www.swas.polito.it/services/concorsi/assric.asp?id_documento_padre=134082
The selected candidate is expected to start his/her appointment on 16th February 2017.
Research topics include:
Vehicular and pedestrian traffic models
Boltzmann-type kinetic equations
Fokker-Planck asymptotic analysis
Multiscale conservation laws, transport of measures</description></item><item><title>Seminar in Trieste: Stefano Marmi</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/12/seminar-in-trieste-stefano-marmi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 15:54:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/12/seminar-in-trieste-stefano-marmi/</guid><description>Wednesday, 14th December 2016, 14:30 - 15:30 (ICTP)
Title: &amp;ldquo;Small divisor problems: some old and new open problems&amp;rdquo;
Venue: Luigi Stasi Seminar Room, ICTP.</description></item><item><title>Floer Postdoctoral Research Fellowship in Mathematics</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/12/floer-postdoctoral-research-fellowship-in-mathematics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 11:56:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/12/floer-postdoctoral-research-fellowship-in-mathematics/</guid><description>The Floer Centre of Geometry invites applications for a 3 years postdoctoral fellowship to pursue research in mathematics at the University of Bochum.
The deadline for applications is January 15, 2017.
Information on the position and instructions for applying can be found at the link: http://www.floer.rub.de/index.html.en</description></item><item><title>17 PhD and 8 postdoc positions - Universities Bochum, Cologne and Münster</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/12/17-phd-and-8-postdoc-positions-universities-bochum-cologne-and-munster/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 11:56:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/12/17-phd-and-8-postdoc-positions-universities-bochum-cologne-and-munster/</guid><description>17 PhD and 8 postdoc positions in mathematics are currently available at the universities of Bochum, Cologne and Münster within the Collaborative Research Centre / Transregio (CRC/TRR 191) on “Symplectic Structures in Geometry, Algebra and Dynamics”.
The deadline for the applications is January 6, 2017.
Information on the projects and instructions for applying can be found at the link: http://www.mi.uni-koeln.de/~geiges/SFB-ausschreibung.pdf
 </description></item><item><title>DAI on Twitter!</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/12/dai-on-twitter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 18:52:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/12/dai-on-twitter/</guid><description>It is with great pleasure that I announce that the DinAmicI now have a Twitter profile! https://twitter.com/DinAmicI
For the moment the tweets will just be pointers to each new post on the DAI website, with proper hashtagging for fast search. More elaborated and/or fun uses may be envisaged for the future.
So follow the @DinAmicI!</description></item><item><title>INdAM-DP-COFUND Ph.D. Fellowships</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/12/indam-dp-cofund-ph-d-fellowships/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 14:37:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/12/indam-dp-cofund-ph-d-fellowships/</guid><description>The INdAM Doctoral Programme fellowships in Mathematics and/or Applications Cofunded by Marie Skłodowska-Curie Actions (INdAM-DP-COFUND-2015) offers fellowships in the framework of the European Horizon 2020 programme “Marie Skłodowska-Curie Co-funding of Regional, National and International Programmes”. These fellowships offer to researchers from all over the world the opportunity to enter a PhD School in Italy.
Application deadlines: 31 March 2017 (Call 1), TBA (Call 2).
More info at: https://cofund.altamatematica.it/dp-2015/main/website
 </description></item><item><title>4 Postdocs in Mathematics at SNS Pisa</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/12/4-postdocs-in-mathematics-at-sns-pisa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 14:30:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/12/4-postdocs-in-mathematics-at-sns-pisa/</guid><description>Selection for 4 post-doc research positions named “Junior Visiting Positions”. The positions will concern the following subject matters:
Position n. 1: Algebraic Geometry and Number Theory;
Position n. 2: Topology, Differential Geometry and Geometric Analysis;
Position n. 3: Partial Differential Equations and Probability;
Position n. 4: Dynamical Systems, as part of the research project “Dynamics and Information Theory Research Institute” (Convenzione 2014 Scuola-Unicredit S.</description></item><item><title>Prima Giornata DinAmica - 25 November 2016</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/11/prima-giornata-dinamica-25-november-2016/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 16:20:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/11/prima-giornata-dinamica-25-november-2016/</guid><description>The First DinAmicI Day to be held at Gran Sasso Science Institute in L&amp;rsquo;Aquila is approaching. For people arriving on the 24th, we are meeting at the restaurant &amp;ldquo;Il primo papavero&amp;rdquo; for dinner.
This is the program of the event (25 November 2016):
9:00-9:50 Mauro Artigiani, &amp;ldquo;Lagrange spectrum of Veech translation surfaces&amp;rdquo; 10:00-10:50 Anna Miriam Benini, &amp;ldquo;Singular values and periodic points&amp;rdquo; 11:00-11:30 Coffee Break 11:30-12:20 Sara Munday, &amp;ldquo;Slippery Devil&amp;rsquo;s Staircases&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Junior postdoc positions in Bologna</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/11/junior-postdoc-positions-in-bologna/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 03:14:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/11/junior-postdoc-positions-in-bologna/</guid><description>The Department of Mathematics of Università di Bologna has opened a call for two 1-year postdoctoral positions denominated &amp;ldquo;Starting postdoctoral position in Mathematics and Applications in Sciences, Social Sciences and Engineering&amp;rdquo;.
The positions are open to all candidates who hold a Ph.D. in Mathematics, Physics, Computer Science, Engineering, Statistics or Economics, with a preference for applicants who have obtained their Ph.D.&amp;rsquo;s in recent years. It is an &amp;ldquo;open&amp;rdquo; position in that all research areas that are currently represented in the Department will be considered (see the announcement for a list of them).</description></item><item><title>Probability postdoc position in Bristol, starting 1 Oct 2017</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/11/probability-postdoc-position-in-bristol-starting-1-oct-2017/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 11:59:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/11/probability-postdoc-position-in-bristol-starting-1-oct-2017/</guid><description>Applications are invited for a 3 year Research Associate role in Mathematics, tenable from 1 October 2017 (or a nearby date to be agreed). The aim of this project, funded by EPSRC UK, is to perform cutting edge research in the following two fields of modern probability theory and stochastic processes: (a) random walks and diffusions with long memory (including self-interacting walks, walks in random environment, tracer diffusion in interacting particle systems); (b) stochastic representations in statistical mechanics with special emphasis on quantum spin and particle systems.</description></item><item><title>Winter School on Conservative Dynamics (5-11 Feb 2017, Engelberg, Switzerland)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/10/winter-school-on-conservative-dynamics-5-11-feb-2017-engelberg-switzerland/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 18:13:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/10/winter-school-on-conservative-dynamics-5-11-feb-2017-engelberg-switzerland/</guid><description>ANNOUNCEMENT
ETH-ITS Winter School on &amp;ldquo;CONSERVATIVE DYNAMICS&amp;rdquo;
Engelberg, Switzerland, 5-11 February 2017.
Courses:
Bassam Fayad (Institut de Mathematiques de Jussieu &amp;amp; CNRS, Paris) &amp;ldquo;Quasi-periodic Birkhoff sums in smooth ergodic theory&amp;rdquo;
Marcel Guardia (Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya, Barcelona) &amp;ldquo;Oscillatory motions in the three body problem&amp;rdquo;
Vadim Kaloshin (University of Maryland and ETH-ITS Zürich) &amp;ldquo;Stochastic Arnol’d diffusion&amp;rdquo;
Alfonso Sorrentino (Universita di Roma “Tor Vergata”) &amp;ldquo;Birkhoff Billiards&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Summer School in Nantes, July 3-7, 2017: Analytical aspects of hyperbolic flows</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/10/summer-school-in-nantes-july-3-7-2017-analytical-aspects-of-hyperbolic-flows/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 15:28:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/10/summer-school-in-nantes-july-3-7-2017-analytical-aspects-of-hyperbolic-flows/</guid><description>Organization board: Sebastien Gouëzel, Laurent Guillopé, Samuel Tapie
Scientific board: Nalini Anantharaman, Viviane Baladi, Colin Guillarmou, Masato Tsujii
Three mini-courses presenting complementary aspects and techniques on hyperbolic flows will form the core of this Summer School. They will be given by S. Dyatlov (M.I.T.), L. Flaminio (U. Lille 1) and C. Liverani (U. Roma Tor Vergata).
Research talks will complete these mini-courses, given by: A. Drouot (U. Berkeley), F. Faure (U.</description></item><item><title>Seminar in Trieste: Giovanni Panti</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/09/seminar-in-trieste-giovanni-panti/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 16:06:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/09/seminar-in-trieste-giovanni-panti/</guid><description>Tuesday 4th October at 17:00 (ICTP)
&amp;ldquo;A geometric model for the natural extension of continued fraction maps&amp;rdquo;
Abstract: Just as classical &amp;ldquo;Floor&amp;rdquo; continued fractions induce the Gauss map on the real unit interval, other euclidean division algorithms (Ceiling, Even, Odd, NearestInteger, &amp;hellip;) induce piecewise-fractional maps with integer coefficients. All these maps have natural extensions that can easily be described on an ad hoc basis.
We present a general framework for dealing with all these maps in a uniform way.</description></item><item><title>Prima Giornata DinAmica - 25 November 2016</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/09/prima-giornata-dinamica-25-novembre-2016/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 07:46:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/09/prima-giornata-dinamica-25-novembre-2016/</guid><description>This is a call for the participation of all DinAmicI to the Prima Giornata DinAmica, our first social meeting to be held on 25 November at the Gran Sasso Science Institute in L&amp;rsquo;Aquila.
There will be seminars by Mauro Artigiani, Anna Miriam Benini and Marcello Seri in the morning. Whereas the afternoon will be devoted to the assembly of the DinAmicI, in which we will discuss possible directions of development of the group.</description></item><item><title>1 year post-doc in Naples (Funded by ERC - Prof. G. Pinzari)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/09/1-year-post-doc-in-naples-funded-by-erc-prof-g-pinzari/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 18:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/09/1-year-post-doc-in-naples-funded-by-erc-prof-g-pinzari/</guid><description>Here is the announcement of 1 yearly post-doc position funded by the ERC StG &amp;ldquo;Stable and Chaotic Motions in the Planetary Problem&amp;rdquo;, at the University of Naples &amp;ldquo;Federico II&amp;rdquo;, Department of Mathematics and Applications. Deadline: 10 October, 2016 (1:30 p.m.)
Link: http://www.unina.it/documents/11958/12921780/MA_03_2016_TIPB_Bando_10.pdf/dd341992-dbdc-4562-8e2a-47fe6ff92bfb</description></item><item><title>Workshop DinAmicI V, 5-9 June 2017</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/09/workshop-dinamici-v-5-9-june-2017/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 10:57:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/09/workshop-dinamici-v-5-9-june-2017/</guid><description>It is a pleasure to announce that our biennial meeting to be held in 2017, will take place in Rome in the week 5-9 June.
It will be sponsored by INdAM with the title
&amp;ldquo;Workshop INdAM - DinAmicI V - Modern Trends in the Ergodic Theory of Dynamical Systems&amp;rdquo;
and have agreed to be part of the scientific committee: Carlangelo Liverani, Yakov Sinai and Lai-Sang Young.
More information and a website will appear soon.</description></item><item><title>Workshop on Hyperbolic Dynamics | Trieste | June 2017</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/09/workshop-on-hyperbolic-dynamics-trieste-june-2017/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 05:54:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/09/workshop-on-hyperbolic-dynamics-trieste-june-2017/</guid><description>The workshop will be held at ICTP, Trieste, 19-23 June 2017. Particular emphasis will be devoted to the core topics which have benefited from the seminal contributions of Yakov Pesin: nonuniform hyperbolicity, dimension theory, thermodynamical formalism.
Speakers: Bunimovich, Buzzi, Denker, Dolgopyat, Hochman, A. Katok, S. Katok, Khanin, Ledrappier, Liverani, Luzzatto, Pesin, Pollicott, F. Rodriguez-Hertz, Sarig, Schmeling, Senti, Shub, Viana, Wilkinson, Zhang
Organizers: Dmitry Dolgopyat, Federico Rodriguez-Hertz, Omri Sarig. Local Organiser: Stefano Luzzatto.</description></item><item><title>2-year PostDoc position in dynamical systems at SNS Pisa</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/09/2-year-postdoc-position-in-dynamical-systems-at-sns-pisa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 17:34:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/09/2-year-postdoc-position-in-dynamical-systems-at-sns-pisa/</guid><description>[Message from Stefano Marmi]
Dear Collegue,
I would be grateful if you could bring to the attention of your best postgraduate students and PhD holders that a two years long research position in “Dynamical systems, computational ergodic theory, randomness and pseudo-randomness” is available at the Scuola Normale Superiore in Pisa.
PhD students can also apply, provided they obtain their PhD no later than 31st december 2016.
*Deadline for application is September 26th 2016.</description></item><item><title>Seminar in Trieste: Raúl Ures</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/09/seminar-in-trieste-raul-ures/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 15:46:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/09/seminar-in-trieste-raul-ures/</guid><description>Thursday 29th September at 16:30 (ICTP)
&amp;ldquo;Ergodicity and Partial Hyperbolicity on Unit Tangent Bundles of Sufaces&amp;rdquo;
Abstract: A diffeomorphism is partially hyperbolic if the tangent bundle of the ambient manifold splits into three invariant sub-bundles, \(TM = E_s \oplus E_c \oplus E_u\), in such a way that \(df\) contracts the vectors of \(E_s\) and expands the vectors of \(E_u\) while the vectors of \(E_c\) have an intermediate behavior. We will present some new advances in the study of the ergodicity of volume preserving partially hyperbolic diffeomorphisms acting on the unit tangent bundle of hyperbolic surfaces.</description></item><item><title>Colloquium at Tor Vergata: Walter Craig (McMaster University) 12 Sept 2016</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/09/colloquium-walter-craig-mcmaster-university-12-sept-2016/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/09/colloquium-walter-craig-mcmaster-university-12-sept-2016/</guid><description>DEPARTMENT COLLOQUIUM
12 SEPTEMBER 2016 , 15.00 (A refreshment will follow in the common room)
AULA DAL PASSO - DEPARTMENT OF MATHEMATICS
UNIVERSITA' DI ROMA &amp;ldquo;TOR VERGATA&amp;rdquo;
Speaker: Prof. Walter Craig (McMaster University)
Title: Vortex Filament Dynamics
Abstract The evolution of vortex filaments in three dimensions is an important problem in mathematical hydrodynamics. It appears in questions on solutions of the Euler equations as well as in the fine structure of vortex filamentation in a superfluid.</description></item><item><title>Seminar in Trieste: Abbas Fakhari</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/08/seminar-in-trieste-abbas-fakhari/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 09:03:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/08/seminar-in-trieste-abbas-fakhari/</guid><description>Thursday 18th August at 14:30 (ICTP)
&amp;ldquo;Ergodicity of Surface Actions via Flag Manifold&amp;rdquo;
Abstract: This talk is devoted to study the ergodicity of smooth surface actions. We provide a sufficient condition for surface actions to be ergodic with respect to the Lebesgue measure. First, we address the main results obtained so far for the unit circle, as a main tool in higher dimensional. After that, by introducing the notion of flag manifold, we explain how rich minimality of sufficiently smooth action on the flag manifold may lead to the ergodicity of the initial action.</description></item><item><title>Senior postdoc position in Bologna</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/08/senior-postdoc-position-in-bologna/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 09:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/08/senior-postdoc-position-in-bologna/</guid><description>The Department of Mathematics of Università di Bologna has opened a call for a 1+1-year postdoctoral position denominated &amp;ldquo;Advanced postdoctoral position in Mathematics and Applications in Sciences, Social Sciences and Engineering&amp;rdquo;.
The position is open to all candidates who hold a Ph.D. in Mathematics, Physics, Computer Science, Engineering, Statistics or Economics and have been involved in postgraduate research activities for at least two years (counting from the application&amp;rsquo;s deadline, September 8, 2016, 1:00PM, CET).</description></item><item><title>Report of the consultation on Mathematics in Horizon 2020</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/08/report-of-the-consultation-on-mathematics-in-horizon-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 08:42:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/08/report-of-the-consultation-on-mathematics-in-horizon-2020/</guid><description>News for the European Commission about Horizon 2020 and Mathematics:
&amp;ldquo;The online consultation on mathematics was carried out from 29 January to 15 May 2016 by the European Commission Directorate General for Communications Networks, Content &amp;amp; Technology (DG CONNECT) in the context of a stakeholder consultation to prepare the Horizon 2020 Work Programme 2018-2020.&amp;rdquo;
More info: https://ec.europa.eu/digital-single-market/en/news/report-consultation-mathematics-horizon-2020</description></item><item><title>ICTP-INdAM Research in Pairs in Mathematics</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/08/ictp-indam-research-in-pairs-in-mathematics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 08:37:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/08/ictp-indam-research-in-pairs-in-mathematics/</guid><description>ICTP and the Istituto Nazionale di Alta Matematica (INdAM) have launched a joint program of &amp;ldquo;Research in Pairs&amp;rdquo; aimed to fund research project in Mathematics to be carried out in collaboration between mathematicians from developing countries and INdAM members either at ICTP in Trieste or in any research unit of INdAM (see the list at http://www.altamatematica.it/it/node/43).
Applications must be submitted using the online system https://e-applications.ictp.it/applicant/login/math_pairs; the deadline is 15 September 2016.</description></item><item><title>Seminar in Trieste: Pablo Carrasco</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/08/seminar-in-trieste-pablo-carrasco/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 08:37:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/08/seminar-in-trieste-pablo-carrasco/</guid><description>Thursday 4th August at 14:30 (ICTP)
&amp;ldquo;Geometric constructions of Equilibrium States&amp;rdquo;
Abstract: In this talk I&amp;rsquo;ll show a completely different construction of equilibrium states associated to Hölder potentials for hyperbolic systems, and indicate the necessary modifications to deal with certain partially hyperbolic cases. The key point for this extension is avoiding altoghether the use of symbolic dynamics and the Perron-Frobenious method. Time permiting I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss applications. This is a joint project with F.</description></item><item><title>Seminar in Trieste: Ian Melbourne</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/07/seminar-in-trieste-ian-melbourne/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 13:53:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/07/seminar-in-trieste-ian-melbourne/</guid><description>Wednesday 17th August at 14:30 (ICTP)
&amp;ldquo;Martingale approximation for parametrised dynamical systems&amp;rdquo;
Abstract: In joint work with Alexey Korepanov and Zemer Kosloff, we prove statistical limit laws for sequences of the type \(\sum_{j=0}^{n-1}v_n\circ T_n^j\) where \(T_n\) is a family of nonuniformly hyperbolic transformations. The key ingredient is a new martingale-coboundary decomposition for nonuniformly hyperbolic transformations which is useful in the case when the family \(T_n\) is replaced by a fixed transformation \(T\), but which is particularly useful in the case when \(T_n\) varies with \(n\).</description></item><item><title>Mini-course on Double Resonances at IHP Paris on December 12-16, 2016</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/07/mini-course-on-double-resonances-at-ihp-paris-on-december-12-16-2016/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 07:47:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/07/mini-course-on-double-resonances-at-ihp-paris-on-december-12-16-2016/</guid><description>Mini-course on Double Resonances on December 12-16, 2016 Jean-Pierre Marco and Vadim Kaloshin will give a mini-course on
Double resonances in the problem of Arnold diffusion
during the week of December 12-16, 2016, in Institut Henri Poincaré (lecture room 201) in Paris. They will address such issues as normal forms along double resonances, singular cylinders, genericity, invariant sets, and local transitivity. The goal is to explain some of the technical details to the audience and to confront their viewpoints.</description></item><item><title>Chaotic phenomena in mathematical models</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/07/chaotic-phenomena-in-mathematical-models/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 21:38:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/07/chaotic-phenomena-in-mathematical-models/</guid><description>At the end of the Pisa-Hokkaido, 2016 summer school, there will be a small workshop involving dynamics.
Chaotic phenomena in mathematical models
(for general information on the whole school )</description></item><item><title>Bandi di concorso per ricercatore a tempo indeterminato</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/07/bandi-di-concorso-per-ricercatore-a-tempo-indeterminato/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 08:11:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/07/bandi-di-concorso-per-ricercatore-a-tempo-indeterminato/</guid><description>E’ stato pubblicato il bando 368.15 per l&amp;rsquo;Area strategica Matematica Applicata per l’assunzione, con contratto di lavoro a tempo pieno e indeterminato, di n. 2 unità di personale con il profilo di Ricercatore, presso strutture del Consiglio Nazionale delle Ricerche con sede in una delle seguenti città: Pavia, Roma.
http://150.146.18.54/iacsite/index.php?page=list_events_new&amp;amp;cod=604</description></item><item><title>Dynamical Systems School - ICTP, Trieste - July 2016.</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/06/dynamical-systems-school-ictp-trieste-july-2016/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 14:01:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/06/dynamical-systems-school-ictp-trieste-july-2016/</guid><description>The school &amp;ldquo;Algebraic, Geometric and Probabilistic Aspects of Dynamical Systems and Control Theory&amp;rdquo; will be held at ICTP Trieste, 4 - 15 July 2016.
Courses: Counting Techniques (S. Filip), Introduction to smooth group actions and rigidity (F. Hertz), Symbolic dynamics for low-dimensional systems with positive entropy (Y. Lima), Dynamics of group actions on homogeneous spaces (A. Mohammadi), Kerov-Vershik method in Pickrell&amp;rsquo;s classification (Y. Qiu), Brownian motion, evolving geometries and entropy formulas (A.</description></item><item><title>A question on periodic orbits for billiards</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/06/a-question-on-periodic-orbits-for-billiards/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 09:47:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/06/a-question-on-periodic-orbits-for-billiards/</guid><description>In section 2.9 of the book &amp;ldquo;Notes on Dynamical Systems&amp;rdquo; by Moser and Zehnder, it is proved the following theorem as a corollary of the Poincaré-Birkhoff fixed point theorem:
Theorem: On a strictly convex billiard table, there exist infinitely many distinct periodic orbits.
Is the result, or a weaker version of it, still true for convex tables?</description></item><item><title>11 GSSI PhD fellowships in Mathematics</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/06/11-gssi-phd-fellowships-in-mathematics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 10:38:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/06/11-gssi-phd-fellowships-in-mathematics/</guid><description>The new call for the Gran Sasso Science Institute (GSSI) PhD fellowships has been published at
http://www.gssi.it/phd/
The Math program offers 11 fellowships including 1 supported by IIT, on Communication Networks of Plant Roots.
The GSSI is a newly established International Graduate School with student from more than 30 different nationalities.
The fellowship gross amount is 16,159 euro per year, plus free lodging in the GSSI premises and free access to the GSSI canteen at lunch time, during working days.</description></item><item><title>Seminar in Pisa: Vitaly Bergelson</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/05/seminar-in-pisa-vitaly-bergelson/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 08:34:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/05/seminar-in-pisa-vitaly-bergelson/</guid><description>Thursday 9th June, h 16:00
Aula Magna, Dipartimento di Matematica, Pisa
Vitaly Bergelson (Ohio State University)
&amp;ldquo;Ergodic Ramsey Theory: the Meeting point of Dynamics and Combinatorics&amp;rdquo;
Abstract: The goal of this talk is to demonstrate the dynamical underpinning of some old and new results in combinatorics and number theory. The results to be discussed include Schur&amp;rsquo;s theorem on Fermat equation over finite fields, theorems of van der Waerden and Szemeredi on arithmetic progressions and some of modern developments involving multiple recurrence along polynomials and applications to the patterns in primes.</description></item><item><title>DinAmicI V in 2017</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/05/dinamici-v-in-2017/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 10:30:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/05/dinamici-v-in-2017/</guid><description>This is a preliminary announcement of the biennial meeting of the &amp;ldquo;DinAmicI&amp;rdquo; group.
The fifth meeting, expected in 2017, has been selected as &amp;ldquo;Workshop INdAM&amp;rdquo;. It will be sponsored by INdAM and held in Rome.
Further news coming soon!</description></item><item><title>"Analytical Methods in Classical and Quantum Dynamical Systems" - Pisa, June 2016</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/05/analytical-methods-in-classical-and-quantum-dynamical-systems-pisa-june-2016/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 10:19:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/05/analytical-methods-in-classical-and-quantum-dynamical-systems-pisa-june-2016/</guid><description>The workshop &amp;ldquo;Analytical Methods in Classical and Quantum Dynamical Systems&amp;rdquo; will be held in Pisa, from June 27 until July 2, 2016, at the Centro &amp;ldquo;De Giorgi&amp;rdquo;.
For all information see http://www.crm.sns.it/event/361/index.html#title</description></item><item><title>8 permanent positions in Mathematics at UFAL - Brazil</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/04/8-permanent-positions-in-mathematics-at-ufal-brazil/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 12:37:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/04/8-permanent-positions-in-mathematics-at-ufal-brazil/</guid><description>The Institute of Mathematics of the Federal University of Alagoas (UFAL), Maceio, Brazil announces 8 (eight) permanent positions in Mathematics. The positions are open to PhDs in Mathematics with a background in Dynamical Systems, Differential Geometry, Algebra and Analysis.
The starting salary will be 8.639 Brazilian Reals per month and the ending salary is 15.956.
The deadline for application is May 12th, 2016. The exams are expected to happen in mid July and a successful candidate expected to take his or her job by the end of the year.</description></item><item><title>JISD 2016 (UPC Barcelona, 11-15 July 2016)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/02/jisd-2016-upc-barcelona-11-15-july-2016/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 19:06:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/02/jisd-2016-upc-barcelona-11-15-july-2016/</guid><description>JISD2016
http://www.ma1.upc.edu/recerca/jisd/jisd2016
14th WORKSHOP ON INTERACTIONS BETWEEN DYNAMICAL SYSTEMS AND PARTIAL DIFFERENTIAL EQUATIONS (JISD2016) Barcelona, July 11 - 15, 2016, at the FME-UPC Lecturers: - Carlangelo Liverani (Università di Roma &amp;ldquo;Tor Vergata&amp;rdquo;) - Bassam Fayad (Institut de Mathématiques de Jussieu) - Felix Otto (Max-Planck-Institute for Mathematics in the Sciences, Leipzig) - Juncheng Wei (University of British Columbia, Vancouver) uOrganizers/u: - Xavier Cabré - Amadeu Delshams - Maria del Mar González - Marcel Guàrdia - Tere M.</description></item><item><title>Two Ph.D. positions in Amsterdam</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/02/two-ph-d-positions-in-amsterdam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 09:00:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/02/two-ph-d-positions-in-amsterdam/</guid><description>The KdV Institute for Mathematics of the University of Amsterdam offers two Ph.D. positions in Dynamical Systems and Complex Analysis at the University of Amsterdam.
Looking for candidates with a MSc degree in Mathematics. A strong background in analysis, and in particular in dynamical systems and/or complex analysis, is a plus.
The official advertisement can be found here: http://www.uva.nl/en/research/phd/phd-vacancies/item/16-056_2-phd-candidates-in-analysis.html
The positions are for 4 years and should lead to a Ph.</description></item><item><title>Seminar Prof. Heinz Hanssmann (University of Utrecht)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/02/seminar-prof-heinz-hanssmann-university-of-utrecht/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 20:08:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/02/seminar-prof-heinz-hanssmann-university-of-utrecht/</guid><description>Prof. Heinz Hanssmann (University of Utrecht)
“Families of hyperbolic Hamiltonian tori”
Thursday 11 February 2016, 15.00
Dipartimento di Matematica (aula Dal Passo) Università di Roma “Tor Vergata”
Abstract:
In integrable Hamiltonian systems hyperbolic tori form families, parametrised by the actions conjugate to the toral angles. The union over such a family is a normally hyperbolic invariant manifold. Under Diophantine conditions a hyperbolic torus persists a small perturbation away from integrability. Locally around such a torus the normally hyperbolic invariant manifold is the centre manifold of that torus and persists as well.</description></item><item><title>Dynamical systems in logic, complex analysis and ergodic theory</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/02/dynamical-systems-in-logic-complex-analysis-and-ergodic-theory/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 16:44:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/02/dynamical-systems-in-logic-complex-analysis-and-ergodic-theory/</guid><description>The workshop &amp;ldquo;Dynamical systems in logic, complex analysis and ergodic theory&amp;rdquo; will be held in Pisa, from February 8 until 9, 2016.
For all information see http://pagine.dm.unipi.it/workshoppra/</description></item><item><title>Seminar in Pisa: Anna Miriam Benini</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/01/seminar-in-pisa-anna-miriam-benini/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 11:09:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/01/seminar-in-pisa-anna-miriam-benini/</guid><description>Wednesday 27th January 2016, h 15:00
Sala Conferenze, Collegio Puteano, Centro De Giorgi, Pisa
Anna Miriam Benini (University of Roma Tor Vergata)
“Permutable entire functions and multiply connnected wandering domains”
Abstract: Let f and g be permutable transcendental entire functions. It is a long standing question whether the Julia sets of f and g are equal. The conjecture is true in the case that f,g are rational functions, and in the transcendental case the main issues are due to the presence of Baker Domains and Wandering Domains.</description></item><item><title>Ph.D. Fellowships at the BCAM, Bilbao</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/01/ph-d-fellowships-at-the-bcam-bilbao/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 16:24:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2016/01/ph-d-fellowships-at-the-bcam-bilbao/</guid><description>In the framework of the initiative funded by &amp;ldquo;la Caixa&amp;rdquo; Foundation, BCAM – Basque Center for Applied Mathematics, as a Severo Ochoa research Centre has opened an international call for researchers, offering three-positions for PhD Fellowships in the center Research Lines:
CFD-CT (supervisor: Johan Jansson) RFES (supervisor: David Pardo) FM (supervisor: Carlos Pérez) SP (supervisor: Gianni Pagnini) ML (supervisor: Jose Antonio Lozano) For further information visit the website: http://www.</description></item><item><title>3-year research associate position in Loughborough</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/12/3-year-research-associate-position-in-loughborough/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 04:02:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/12/3-year-research-associate-position-in-loughborough/</guid><description>3-year post-doctoral research associate position in ergodic theory and dynamical systems at Loughborough University, UK:
https://vacancies.lboro.ac.uk/tlive_webrecruitment/wrd/run/ETREC107GF.open?VACANCY_ID%3d2538536IOU%1BUSESSION=0FB51543F51C4220B475A68B31B63BDC&amp;amp;WVID=5913100PrZ&amp;amp;LANG=USA
Deadline to apply: 13 January 2016
(Skype) Interviews: 26 January 2016
Start date: 1 May 2016</description></item><item><title>Post-doc position at Scuola Normale Superiore - Pisa</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/12/post-doc-position-at-scuola-normale-superiore-pisa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 18:27:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/12/post-doc-position-at-scuola-normale-superiore-pisa/</guid><description>The Scuola Normale Superiore announces a selection for 4 post-doc research positions named “Junior Visiting Positions”. The positions will be in the following subject matters:
Position n.1: Algebraic Geometry and Number Theory;
Position n.2: Topology, Differential Geometry and Geometric Analysis;
Position n.3: Partial Differential Equations and Probability;
Position n.4: Dynamical Systems and Information Theory, as part of the research project “Dynamics and Information Theory Research Institute” (Convenzione 2014 Scuola - Unicredit S.</description></item><item><title>PhD studentship in Exeter</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/12/phd-studentship-in-exeter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2015 03:14:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/12/phd-studentship-in-exeter/</guid><description>Funded Ph.D. studentship with Dalia Terhesiu at the University of Exeter:
http://www.exeter.ac.uk/studying/funding/award/?id=2035
Deadline for application: 17th January 2016</description></item><item><title>Streaming Colloquium Vadim Kaloshin (2/12/2015, 15:30)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/12/streaming-colloquium-vadim-kaloshin-2122015-1530/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 17:57:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/12/streaming-colloquium-vadim-kaloshin-2122015-1530/</guid><description>We announce that the COLLOQUIUM at the Department of Mathematics, University of Roma Tor Vergata, by Prof. Vadim Kaloshin, University of Maryland (USA), will be available on Wednesday, December 2, at 15:30, live on streaming at
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qVLqwZFvUU4
The title of the talk is:
&amp;ldquo;Stochastic Arnold diffusion in deterministic systems and celestial mechanics&amp;rdquo;.
This will be our first attempt to make colloquia on streaming; we apologize in advance for any unforeseen problem.</description></item><item><title>Postdoc position in Bilbao</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/11/postdoc-position-in-bilbao/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 18:49:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/11/postdoc-position-in-bilbao/</guid><description>Two-year postdoc position at the Basque Center for Applied Mathematics, Bilbao, on &amp;ldquo;Stochastic Processes for Anomalous Diffusion&amp;rdquo;.
Deadline: 30th December 2015.
Description</description></item><item><title>"Renormalization in Dynamics" - Pisa, April 2016</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/11/renormalization-in-dynamics-pisa-april-2016/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 10:52:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/11/renormalization-in-dynamics-pisa-april-2016/</guid><description>The conference &amp;ldquo;Renormalization in Dynamics&amp;rdquo; will be held in Pisa, from April 4 until 8, 2016.
For all information see http://www.crm.sns.it/event/360/
There will be financial support for PhD students and young PostDocs. The deadline for application is 15th January 2016.</description></item><item><title>INdAM Outgoing, Incoming and Reintegration fellowships</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/11/indam-fellowships-for-outgoing-incoming-and-reintegration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 16:33:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/11/indam-fellowships-for-outgoing-incoming-and-reintegration/</guid><description>The third call for the INdAM COFUND-2012 fellowships is now open. The deadline is Thursday 10 December 2015, 17:00 (Rome local time).
https://cofund.altamatematica.it/2012/main/website</description></item><item><title>Bruin's seminar in Pisa</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/10/bruins-seminar-in-pisa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 13:06:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/10/bruins-seminar-in-pisa/</guid><description>Thursday 12th November 2015, h 9:30 Sala Conferenze, Collegio Puteano, Centro De Giorgi, Pisa
Henk Bruin (University of Vienna)
&amp;ldquo;Sharp mixing rates via inducing with respect to general return times&amp;rdquo;
Abstract: For non-uniformly expanding maps inducing w.r.t. a general (i.e., not necessarily first) return time to Gibbs Markov maps, we provide sufficient conditions for obtaining sharp estimates for the correlation function. This applies to both the finite and the infinite measure setting.</description></item><item><title>Sorrentino's seminar in Pisa</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/10/sorrentinos-seminar-in-pisa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 10:47:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/10/sorrentinos-seminar-in-pisa/</guid><description>Monday 9th November 2015, h 15:00 - 17:00 Aula Seminari (Dipartimento di Matematica, Pisa)
Alfonso Sorrentino (Università di Roma &amp;ldquo;Tor Vergata&amp;rdquo;)
“AUBRY-MATHER THEORY FOR TWIST MAPS AND BILLIARDS”
This is a special meeting of the &amp;ldquo;Mathematical Physics Working Group&amp;rdquo; of the Mathematical Department of the University of Pisa, and will be of introductory level.</description></item><item><title>Postdoc position in Bristol</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/10/post-doc-position-in-bristol/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 07:26:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/10/post-doc-position-in-bristol/</guid><description>1-yr (potentially 2-yr) postdoctoral position with Corinna Ulcigrai at the University of Bristol:
http://www.bristol.ac.uk/jobs/find/details.html?nPostingId=3764&amp;amp;nPostingTargetId=13751&amp;amp;id=Q50FK026203F3VBQBV7V77V83&amp;amp;LG=UK&amp;amp;mask=uobext
 </description></item><item><title>"Geometric Aspects of Modern Dynamics", Oporto, January 2016</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/09/geometric-aspects-of-modern-dynamics-oporto-january-2016/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 08:14:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/09/geometric-aspects-of-modern-dynamics-oporto-january-2016/</guid><description>The conference &amp;ldquo;Geometric Aspects of Modern Dynamics&amp;rdquo; will be held in Oporto (Portugal) from January 11 until 15, 2016:
http://cmup.fc.up.pt/complexdynamics/
Organizing Committee: Jasmin Raissy (U. Toulouse, France) Helena Reis (U. Porto, Portugal)
Scientific Committee: Marco Abate (U. Pisa, Italy) Alexey Glutsuyk (ENS-Lyon, France) Misha Lyubich (SUNY-SB, US) Julio Rebelo (U. Toulouse, France) Helena Reis (U. Porto, Portugal)</description></item><item><title>Aberystwyth Studentships Available</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/09/aberystwyth-studentships-available/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 08:08:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/09/aberystwyth-studentships-available/</guid><description>Up to three fully-funded studentships are available for highly-motivated candidates to undertake PhD research within the Department of Mathematics at Aberystwyth University.
The research group in Mathematical Modelling of Structures, Solids and Fluids has an international reputation in the study of complex fluids and structures, offering a unified approach to the mathematical modelling, computation and analysis of materials.
Projects should be in the area of mathematical modelling of multiphysics phenomena in complex materials with microstructure, for example deformation, waves, fracture and damage propagation in inhomogeneous structures.</description></item><item><title>Université de Montréal opening for tenure-track professor in Analysis</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/09/universite-de-montreal-opening-for-tenure-track-professor-in-analysis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 01:52:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/09/universite-de-montreal-opening-for-tenure-track-professor-in-analysis/</guid><description>Poste analyse / Position in analysis
 </description></item><item><title>Tenure-track faculty position at Queen's</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/09/tenure-track-faculty-position-at-queens/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 01:45:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/09/tenure-track-faculty-position-at-queens/</guid><description>https://www.mathjobs.org/jobs/jobs/7646</description></item><item><title>Position as Type B Researcher in Rome Sapienza</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/09/position-as-type-b-researcher-in-rome-sapienza/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 07:54:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/09/position-as-type-b-researcher-in-rome-sapienza/</guid><description>The Department of Mathematics of University of Rome Sapienza offers a position as a Type B Researcher (Ricercatore a Tempo Determinato di tipo B) in Mathematical Physics (Settore Scientifico Disciplinare MAT/07). The deadline for application is 17 September 2015.
All the details can be found at the following address: www2.uniroma1.it/organizzazione/amministrazione/ripartizionepersonale/concorsi/ricercatori_tempo_determinato/default.php
 </description></item><item><title>Pollicott's seminar in Pisa</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/09/pollicotts-seminar-in-pisa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 17:21:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/09/pollicotts-seminar-in-pisa/</guid><description>Thursday 03/9/2015, h 16:30 Sala Conferenze (Puteano, Centro De Giorgi)
Mark Pollicott (University of Warwick)
“LINEAR RESPONSE AND PERIODIC ORBITS”</description></item><item><title>Lecture notes: "Statistical properties of dynamics. Introduction to the functional analytic approach"</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/08/lecture-notes-statistical-properties-of-dynamics-introduction-to-the-functional-analytic-approach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 15:49:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/08/lecture-notes-statistical-properties-of-dynamics-introduction-to-the-functional-analytic-approach/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m uploading the lecture notes of a minicourse, in the Pisa-Hokkaido summer school 2015.
It is a very elementary approach to the subject, intended for advanced undergaduate students or first years Ph.D. ones. Notes_2015_hokudai2</description></item><item><title>Lecture notes on "Complessità Caos Informazione"</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/08/lecture-notes-on-caos-complessita-informazione/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 10:42:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/08/lecture-notes-on-caos-complessita-informazione/</guid><description>I am uploading the lecture notes of a course I gave in Camerino in the academic years 2003-2004 and 2004-2005.
Complessità Caos Informazione</description></item><item><title>Dynamical aspects of number theory talks in Cortona</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/07/dynamical-aspects-of-number-theory-talks-in-cortona/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 13:22:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/07/dynamical-aspects-of-number-theory-talks-in-cortona/</guid><description>On Thursday 3rd September there will be a special session at the 17th European Women in Maths general meeting in Cortona on &amp;ldquo;Dynamical aspects of number theory&amp;rdquo;. It runs from 10:00 - 13:00, and there will be short talks by Valerie Berthé, Karma Dajani, Charlene Kalle, Henna Koivusalo and Nicola Oswald.
Registration for the conference is unfortunately already closed, but if anyone is nearby and wants to come only for this morning session, I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine there would be any problem.</description></item><item><title>Cellarosi's seminar in Bologna, July 22, 2015</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/07/cellarosis-seminar-in-bologna-july-22-2015/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 08:58:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/07/cellarosis-seminar-in-bologna-july-22-2015/</guid><description>When: Wednesday July 22, 2015, at 11:30
Where: Seminario I, Dept. of Mathematics, Università di Bologna
Who: Francesco Cellarosi (Queen&amp;rsquo;s University, Canada)
What: Seminar &amp;ldquo;Recent progress towards Sarnak’s and Chowla’s Conjectures&amp;rdquo;
Abstract: I will present an overview of Sarnak’s conjecture on the disjointness of the Möbius function from any deterministic sequence and the related Chowla’s conjecture on the self-correlations of the Möbius function. Some progress towards weaker versions of these conjectures have been made recently, and I plan to illustrate them.</description></item><item><title>De Simoi's seminar in Pisa</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/07/de-simois-seminar-in-pisa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 08:46:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/07/de-simois-seminar-in-pisa/</guid><description>Monday 20/7/2015, h 11:30-12:30 Sala Conferenze (Puteano, Centro De Giorgi)
Jacopo De Simoi (University of Toronto)
&amp;ldquo;AN INTEGRABLE BILLIARD CLOSE TO AN ELLIPSE OF SMALL ECCENTRICITY IS AN ELLIPSE&amp;rdquo;
Abstract: In 1927 G. Birkhoff conjectured that if a billiard in a strictly convex smooth domain is integrable, the domain has to be an ellipse (or a circle). The conjecture is still wide open, and presents remarkable relations with open questions in inverse spectral theory and spectral rigidity.</description></item><item><title>How to add a new publication</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/07/how-to-add-a-new-publication/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 21:08:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/07/how-to-add-a-new-publication/</guid><description>Keeping an up-to-date list of publications on our site is important in terms of our visibility as DinAmicI. Adding a new publication (by you or another member of our community) is rather straightforward, but still here are some instructions.
On your back-end page (that you get to by clicking on &amp;ldquo;Site Admin&amp;rdquo; on any of the site&amp;rsquo;s pages), look for &amp;ldquo;Publications&amp;rdquo; in the list on the left. In the pop-up menu, click on &amp;ldquo;Add New&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Vaienti's seminar in Pisa</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/07/seminario-di-vaienti-a-pisa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 15:24:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/07/seminario-di-vaienti-a-pisa/</guid><description>Friday, July 17, 2015, h. 16:00-17:00 Sala Conferenze (Puteano, Centro De Giorgi)
Sandro Vaienti (CPT Marseille)
&amp;ldquo;On recent results of extreme value theory applied to dynamical systems&amp;rdquo;
Abstract: We give a review of a few recent results of extreme value theory applied to random dynamical systems and to coupled lattice maps.</description></item><item><title>How to post</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/07/how-to-post/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2015 08:15:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/07/how-to-post/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;d like to post something on the website click on the &amp;ldquo;site admin&amp;rdquo; link on the main page. You&amp;rsquo;ll find it under &amp;ldquo;Meta links&amp;rdquo; on the left hand side. This will take you to your dashboard where you&amp;rsquo;ll find a &amp;ldquo;Posts&amp;rdquo; link on the top left. Click on the sub-link &amp;ldquo;Add New&amp;rdquo; and you&amp;rsquo;ll be brought to a page where you can create your post. Note that you can add links to webpages, such as www.</description></item><item><title>Cookie Policy</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/cookie-policy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 19:34:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/cookie-policy/</guid><description>Privacy Policy
We are committed to privacy and support current industry initiatives to preserve individual privacy rights on the Internet. Protecting your privacy on-line is an evolving area and this website will constantly evolve to meet these demands.
Cookies
We use a number of different cookies on our site. If you do not know what cookies are, or how to control or delete them, then we recommend you visit http://www.aboutcookies.org for detailed guidance.</description></item><item><title>PhD grant in Dynamical Systems in Barcelona</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/06/phd-grant-in-dynamical-systems-in-barcelona/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 09:56:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/06/phd-grant-in-dynamical-systems-in-barcelona/</guid><description>The Barcelona Graduate school of mathematics (BGSMATH) offers a PhD grant in Dynamical Systems:
http://www.bgsmath.cat/currentopencalls/
Deadline: June 29, 2015, 15:00 (Spanish time)</description></item><item><title>Workshop DinAmicI IV</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/05/workshop-dinamici-iv/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 18:16:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/05/workshop-dinamici-iv/</guid><description>Our beloved biennal workshop, currently titled DinAmicI IV, Fourth Workshop of the Italian Dynamicists, will take place in Corinaldo from Monday the 22th through Thursday the 25th of June 2015.
Web site: https://events.unibo.it/mat-workshop-dinamici2015
 </description></item><item><title>Latex support on this website</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/02/latex-support-on-dai-website/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 16:41:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/02/latex-support-on-dai-website/</guid><description>This website uses MathJax, a JavaScript library able to compile and render latex live in your browser. The syntax is fully explained here: https://wordpress.org/plugins/mathjax-latex/. Briefly:
 display style formulas can be obtained as in the standard latex syntax by typing them between double dollars or escaped square brackets ($$ ... $$ or \[ ... \] ); inline style formulas use the slightly non-standard syntax $latex ... $ or \( .</description></item><item><title>New website</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/02/new-website/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 16:02:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/2015/02/new-website/</guid><description>Thanks to the tireless work of our great Marcello, we now have a wonderful shiny new site!!</description></item></channel></rss>