<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dai-seminars on DinAmicI</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/</link><description>Recent content in Dai-seminars on DinAmicI</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 08:33:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kasun Fernando (University of Toronto, Canada)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/kasun-fernando-university-of-toronto-canada/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 08:33:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/kasun-fernando-university-of-toronto-canada/</guid><description>Speaker: Kasun Fernando (University of Toronto, Canada)
Title: TBA
Abstract: TBA
NOTE: The seminar will be streamed live on our YouTube channel then saved there. If you ask questions, with your video feed on or off, you agree to the use of your image/spoken words for said purpose.</description></item><item><title>Mauro Artigiani (Universidad del Rosario, Colombia)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/mauro-artigiani-universidad-del-rosario-colombia/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 08:31:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/mauro-artigiani-universidad-del-rosario-colombia/</guid><description>Speaker: Mauro Artigiani (Universidad del Rosario, Colombia)
Title: TBA
Abstract: TBA
NOTE: The seminar will be streamed live on our YouTube channel then saved there. If you ask questions, with your video feed on or off, you agree to the use of your image/spoken words for said purpose.</description></item><item><title>Matteo Tanzi (New York University, USA)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/matteo-tanzi-new-york-university-usa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 08:28:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/matteo-tanzi-new-york-university-usa/</guid><description>Speaker: Matteo Tanzi (New York University, USA)
Title: Random-like properties of chaotic forcing
Abstract: We prove that skew systems with a sufficiently expanding base have &amp;ldquo;approximate&amp;rdquo; statistical properties similar to random ergodic Markov chains. For example, they exhibit approximate exponential decay of correlations, meaning that the exponential rate is observed modulo a controlled error. The fiber maps are only assumed to be Lipschitz regular and to depend on the base in a way that guarantees diffusive behaviour on the vertical component.</description></item><item><title>Umberto Zannier (Scuola Normale Superiore, Italy)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/umberto-zannier-scuola-normale-superiore-italy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 08:40:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/umberto-zannier-scuola-normale-superiore-italy/</guid><description>Speaker: Umberto Zannier (Scuola Normale Superiore, Italy)
Title: Torsion values of sections, elliptical billiards and diophantine problems in dynamics
Abstract: After a very brief review of basics on elliptic curves and their families, we shall consider &amp;ldquo;sections&amp;rdquo; of such families, and especially their &amp;ldquo;torsion values&amp;rdquo;. For instance, what can be said of the complex numbers b for which [latex](2, \sqrt{2(2-b)})[/latex] is torsion on the Legendre curve [latex]y^2=x(x-1)(x-b)[/latex]? In particular, we shall recall results of &amp;ldquo;Manin-Mumford type&amp;rdquo; and focus to illustrate some applications to elliptical billiards.</description></item><item><title>Selim Ghazouani (Université d’Orsay, France)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/selim-ghazouani-universite-dorsay-france/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 21:04:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/selim-ghazouani-universite-dorsay-france/</guid><description>Speaker: **Selim Ghazouani ** (Université d’Orsay, France)
Title: Piecewise affine homeomorphisms of the circle and dilation surfaces
*Abstract: *In this talk I will consider the following question: if one picks a piecewise affine map of the circle &amp;ldquo;at random”, what dynamical behaviour are we likely to observe? The case of standard circle diffeomorphisms has been studied by Herman in the 80s; in this emblematic case the problem can be reduced to theorems close to KAM theory.</description></item><item><title>Tanja Schindler (Scuola Normale Superiore, Italy)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/tanja-schindler-scuola-normale-superiore-italy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 22:04:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/tanja-schindler-scuola-normale-superiore-italy/</guid><description>Speaker: Tanja Schindler (Scuola Normale Superiore, Italy)
Title: Almost sure asymptotic behaviour of Birkhoff sums for infinite measure-preserving dynamical systems
Abstract: We are interested in the limit behaviour of Birkhoff sums over an infinite sigma-finite measure space. If the observable is integrable then &amp;ndash; by a classical theorem by Aaronson &amp;ndash; there exists no sequence of real numbers such that the Birkhoff sum normed by this sequence converges almost surely to 1.</description></item><item><title>Eva Miranda (Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya) and Daniel Peralta-Salas (Instituto de Ciencias Matemáticas, Spain)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/eva-miranda-universitat-politecnica-de-catalunya-and-daniel-peralta-salas-instituto-de-ciencias-matematicas-spain/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 09:39:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/eva-miranda-universitat-politecnica-de-catalunya-and-daniel-peralta-salas-instituto-de-ciencias-matematicas-spain/</guid><description>Speakers: Eva Miranda (Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya), Daniel Peralta-Salas (Instituto de Ciencias Matemáticas, Spain)
Title: Looking at Euler flows through a contact mirror: Universality and Turing completeness
Abstract: The dynamics of an inviscid and incompressible fluid flow on a Riemannian manifold is governed by the Euler equations. Recently, Tao launched a programme to address the global existence problem for the Euler and Navier Stokes equations based on the concept of universality.</description></item><item><title>Álvaro del Pino Gómez (Utrecht University, The Netherlands)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/alvaro-del-pino-gomez/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 15:14:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/alvaro-del-pino-gomez/</guid><description>Speaker: Álvaro del Pino Gómez (Utrecht University, The Netherlands)
Title: Billiards in subriemannian geometry
Abstract: When one considers manifolds with boundary, billiard dynamics are the natural analogue of standard geodesic dynamics. Namely, instead of having geodesics escape at the boundary, we force them back into the manifold using the reflection law. In other dynamical settings, similar constructions are possible: In 2006, B. Khesin and S. Tabachnikov initiated the study of billiards in the semiriemannian setting, studying the integrability of various tables.</description></item><item><title>Alessandro Della Corte (Università di Camerino, Italy)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/alessandro-della-corte-universita-di-camerino-italy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 16:22:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/alessandro-della-corte-universita-di-camerino-italy/</guid><description>Speaker: Alessandro Della Corte (Università di Camerino, Italy)
Title: The simplest erasing substitution
*Abstract: *The symbolic action of a substitution on the binary expansion generates naturally an interval map. In case of erasing substitutions, the map is typically Baire-1 and not Darboux. As a model case, we consider what is arguably the simplest erasing substitution, mapping 0s to the empty word and 1s to 0 or 1 depending on the parity.</description></item><item><title>Paolo Giulietti (Università di Pisa, Italy)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/paolo-giulietti-universita-di-pisa-italy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 15:15:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/paolo-giulietti-universita-di-pisa-italy/</guid><description>Speaker: Paolo Giulietti (Università di Pisa, Italy)
Title: Infinite mixing for accessible skew products
*Abstract: *I will present some decay of correlations results on skew products which are locally accessible. The results rely on the study of a twisted transfer operator and could be generalized to many other situations. I will also present numerical counterparts to such results.
NOTE: The seminar will be streamed live on our YouTube channel then saved there.</description></item><item><title>Gary Froyland (University of New South Wales, Australia)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/gary-froyland-university-of-new-south-wales-australia/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 12:12:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/gary-froyland-university-of-new-south-wales-australia/</guid><description>Speaker: Gary Froyland (University of New South Wales, Australia)
Title: The dynamic ocean
Abstract: The circulation of our oceans strongly influences climate, weather and biology. Our ocean currents are dynamic, and fluctuate to varying extents. I will introduce data-driven numerical tools that can tease apart dynamic components of the ocean, with information sourced from ocean drifters, satellite imagery, and ocean models. These components, their lifecycles, and their response to external forcing, help us to build a dynamic picture of our ocean.</description></item><item><title>Misha Bialy (Tel Aviv University, Israel)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/mischa-bialy-tel-aviv-university-israel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 08:29:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/mischa-bialy-tel-aviv-university-israel/</guid><description>Speaker: **Misha Bialy ** (Tel Aviv University, Israel)
Title: Birkhoff-Poritsky conjecture for centrally-symmetric billiards
Abstract: In this talk I shall discuss Birkhoff-Poritsky conjecture for centrally-symmetric C^2-smooth convex planar billiards. We assume that the domain A between the invariant curve of 4-periodic orbits and the boundary of the phase cylinder is foliated by C^0-invariant curves. Under this assumption we prove that the billiard curve is an ellipse. Other versions of Birkhoff-Poritsky conjecture follow from this result.</description></item><item><title>Michele Gianfelice (Università della Calabria, Italy)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/michele-gianfelice-universita-della-calabria-italy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 13:27:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/michele-gianfelice-universita-della-calabria-italy/</guid><description>Speaker: Michele Gianfelice (Università della Calabria, Italy)
Title: Stochastic stability of classical Lorenz flow under impulsive type forcing
*Abstract: *Inspired by the problem of modeling the so called anthropogenic forcing in climatology, e.g. the effects of the emissions of greenhouse gases in the atmosphere, we introduce a novel type of random perturbation for the classical Lorenz flow and prove its stochastic stability. The perturbation acts on the system in an impulsive way, hence is not of diffusive type.</description></item><item><title>Andrea Venturelli (Université d’Avignon, France)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/andrea-venturelli-universite-davignon-france/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 09:00:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/andrea-venturelli-universite-davignon-france/</guid><description>Speaker: Andrea Venturelli (Université d’Avignon, France)
Title: Hyperbolic motion in the Newtonian N-body problem with arbitrary limit shape
*Abstract: *We prove for the N-body problem the existence of hyperbolic motions for any prescribed limit shape and any given initial configuration of the bodies. The energy level h&amp;gt;0 of the motion can also be chosen arbitrarily. Our approach is based on the construction of a global viscosity solutions for the Hamilton-Jacobi equation H(x,du(x))=h.</description></item><item><title>Anna Miriam Benini (Università di Parma, Italy)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/miriam-benini-universita-di-parma-italy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 14:07:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/miriam-benini-universita-di-parma-italy/</guid><description>Speaker: Anna Miriam Benini (Università di Parma, Italy)
Title: Infinite entropy for transcendental entire functions
*Abstract: * Defining entropy on noncompact metric spaces is a tricky business, since there are several natural and nonequivalent generalizations of the usual notions of entropy for continuous maps on compact spaces. By defining entropy for transcendental maps on the complex plane as the sup over the entropy restricted to compact forward invariant subsets, we prove that with this definition the entropy of such functions is infinite.</description></item><item><title>Isaia Nisoli (Universidade Federal do Rio de Janeiro, Brazil)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/isaia-nisoli-universidade-federal-de-rio-de-janeiro-brazil/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 15:00:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/isaia-nisoli-universidade-federal-de-rio-de-janeiro-brazil/</guid><description>Speaker: Isaia Nisoli (Universidade Federal do Rio de Janeiro, Brazil)
Title: A simple system presenting Noise Induced Order
Abstract: In this talk I will present a family of one dimensional systems with random additive noise such that, as the noise size increases, the Lyapunov exponent of the stationary measure transitions from positive to negative. This phenomena is known in literature as Noise Induced Order, and was first observed in a model of the Belosouv-Zhabotinsky reaction and its existence was proven only recently by Galatolo-Monge-Nisoli.</description></item><item><title>Carlangelo Liverani (Università di Roma Tor Vergata, Italy)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/carlangelo-liverani-universita-di-roma-tor-vergata-italy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 13:58:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/carlangelo-liverani-universita-di-roma-tor-vergata-italy/</guid><description>Speaker: Carlangelo Liverani (Università di Roma Tor Vergata, Italy)
Title: Locating Ruelle-Pollicott resonances
Abstract: We study the spectrum of transfer operators associated to various dynamical systems. Our aim is to obtain precise information on discrete spectrum. To this end we propose a unitary approach. We consider various settings where new information can be obtained following different branches along the proposed path. These settings include affine expanding Markov maps, uniformly expanding Markov maps, non-uniformly expanding maps, hyperbolic diffeomorphisms.</description></item><item><title>Stefano Marò (Università di Pisa, Italy)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/stefano-maro-university-of-pisa-italy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 21:29:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/stefano-maro-university-of-pisa-italy/</guid><description>Speaker: Stefano Marò (Università di Pisa, Italy)
Title: Chaotic motion in the breathing circle billiard
Abstract: We consider the free motion of a point particle inside a circular billiard with periodically moving boundary, with the assumption that the collisions of the particle with the boundary are elastic so that the energy of the particle is not preserved. It is known that if the motion of the boundary is regular enough then the energy is bounded due to the existence of invariant curves.</description></item><item><title>Françoise Pène (Université de Bretagne Occidentale, France)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/francoise-pene-universite-de-bretagne-occidentale-france/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 11:00:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/francoise-pene-universite-de-bretagne-occidentale-france/</guid><description>Speaker: Françoise Pène (Université de Bretagne Occidentale, France)
Title: Invariance by induction of the asymptotic variance
Abstract: It is well known that the integral of an observable is preserved by induction. We are interested here in extensions of this result to moments of order 2 and 3. We have two natural candidates for the second and third order moments: the classical asymptotic variance (given by the Green-Kubo formula) and an analogous quantity of the third order.</description></item><item><title>Andreas Knauf (Friedrich-Alexander-Universität Erlangen-Nürnberg, Germany)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/andreas-knauf-friedrich-alexander-universitat-erlangen-nurnberg-germany/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 07:07:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/andreas-knauf-friedrich-alexander-universitat-erlangen-nurnberg-germany/</guid><description>Speaker: Andreas Knauf (Friedrich-Alexander-Universität Erlangen-Nürnberg, Germany)
Title: Asymptotic velocity for scattering particles
*Abstract: *Partly with Jacques Fejoz, Richard Montgomery, Stefan Fleischer and Manuel Quaschner.
The past and future of scattering particle systems is partly determined by their asymptotic velocity, that is, the Cesàro limit of the velocity. That this exists for bounded interactions and all initial conditions, is part of a statement sometimes called &amp;lsquo;asymptotic completeness&amp;rsquo;. The same statement does not apply to individual initial conditions in celestial mechanics.</description></item><item><title>Seminar by Marta Maggioni postponed to July 1</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/seminar-by-marta-maggioni-universiteit-leiden-netherlands-postponed-to-july-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 08:34:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/seminar-by-marta-maggioni-universiteit-leiden-netherlands-postponed-to-july-1/</guid><description>The DinAmicI, in solidarity with the #Strike4BlackLives and #ShutDownSTEM movements on June 10, 2020, acknowledge the racism present throughout academia and especially in STEM subjects. In agreement with our speaker Marta Maggioni, whom we sincerely thank, we have decided to reschedule her talk to July 1st. We apologize for any inconvenience and invite everybody to reflect and take action on systemic inequalities in academia and science.
https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-020-01721-x</description></item><item><title>Sunrose Shrestha (Tufts University, USA)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/sunrose-shrestha-tufts-university-usa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 13:29:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/sunrose-shrestha-tufts-university-usa/</guid><description>Speaker: Sunrose Shrestha (Tufts University, USA)
Title: The topology and geometry of random square-tiled surfaces
Abstract: A square-tiled surface (STS) is a branched cover of the standard square torus with branching over exactly one point. They are concrete examples of translation surfaces which are an important class of singular flat metrics on 2-manifolds with applications in Teichmüller theory and polygonal billiards. In this talk we will consider a randomizing model for STSs based on permutation pairs and use it to compute the genus distribution.</description></item><item><title>Marta Maggioni (Universiteit Leiden, Netherlands)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/marta-maggioni-universiteit-leiden-netherlands/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 19:31:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/marta-maggioni-universiteit-leiden-netherlands/</guid><description>Speaker: **Marta Maggioni ** (Universiteit Leiden, Netherlands)
Title: Matching for random systems with an application to minimal weight expansions
Abstract: We consider families of skew-product maps, representing systems evolving in discrete time in which, at each time step, one of a number of transformations is chosen according to an i.i.d process and applied. We extend the notion of matching for such dynamical systems and we show that, for a certain family of piecewise affine random maps of the interval, the property of random matching implies that any invariant density is piecewise constant.</description></item><item><title>Sandro Vaienti (Centre de Physique Théorique, Marseille, France)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/sandro-vaienti-centre-de-physique-theorique-marseille-france/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 12:24:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/sandro-vaienti-centre-de-physique-theorique-marseille-france/</guid><description>Speaker: **Sandro Vaienti ** (Centre de Physique Théorique, Marseille, France)
Title: Thermodynamic formalism for random weighted covering systems
Abstract: We develop a quenched thermodynamic formalism for random dynamical systems generated by countably branched, piecewise-monotone mappings of the interval that satisfy a random covering condition.
Joint with J. Atnip, G. Froyland and C. Gonzalez-Tokman</description></item><item><title>Francesco Cellarosi (Queen's University, Canada)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/28-5-francesco-cellarosi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 12:22:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/28-5-francesco-cellarosi/</guid><description>Speaker: Francesco Cellarosi (Queen&amp;rsquo;s University, Canada)
Title: Rational Horocycle lifts and the tails of Quadratic Weyl sums
Abstract: Equidistribution of horocycles on hyperbolic surfaces has been used to dynamically answer several probabilistic questions about number-theoretical objects. In this talk we focus on horocycle lifts, i.e. curves on higher-dimensional manifolds whose projection to the hyperbolic surface is a classical horocycle, and their behaviour under the action of the geodesic flow. It is known that when such horocycle lifts are `generic’, then their push forward via the geodesic flow becomes equidistributed in the ambient manifold.</description></item><item><title>Martin Leguil (Université Paris-Sud 11, France)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/martin-leguil-universite-paris-sud-11-france/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 12:20:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/martin-leguil-universite-paris-sud-11-france/</guid><description>Speaker: Martin Leguil (Université Paris-Sud 11, France)
*Title: **Some rigidity results for billiards and hyperbolic flows ***
Abstract: In a project with P. Bálint, J. De Simoi and V. Kaloshin, we have been studying the inverse problem for a class of open dispersing billiards obtained by removing from the plane a finite number of smooth strictly convex scatterers satisfying a non-eclipse condition. The dynamics of such billiards is hyperbolic (Axiom A), and there is a natural labeling of periodic orbits.</description></item><item><title>Giulio Tiozzo (University of Toronto, Canada)</title><link>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/giulio-tiozzo-university-of-toronto-canada/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 12:18:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dai-dinamici.github.io/dai-seminars/giulio-tiozzo-university-of-toronto-canada/</guid><description>Speaker: Giulio Tiozzo (University of Toronto, Canada)
Title: Central limit theorems for counting measures in coarse negative curvature
Abstract: We establish general central limit theorems for an action of a group on a hyperbolic space with respect to counting for the word length in the group.
In 2013, Chas, Li, and Maskit produced numerical experiments on random closed geodesics on a hyperbolic pair of pants. Namely, they drew uniformly at random conjugacy classes of a given word length, and considered the hyperbolic length of the corresponding closed geodesic on the pair of pants.</description></item></channel></rss>